<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>虚拟货币新闻</title>
        <link>Your Website URL</link>
        <description>Description of Your RSS Feed</description>
    <item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Is Bitcoin price bouncing at 57K? Here's why these levels are key

URL Source: https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-price-bouncing-57k-why-these-levels-key

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:09:58.000Z

Markdown Content:
Bitcoin ([BTC](https://cointelegraph.com/bitcoin-price)) held near two-month lows at the May 1 Wall Street open as risk assets braced themselves for the next United States macro move.

![Image 1](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/a3041030-8234-41e9-83d4-5eaf5c719491.png)

_BTC/USD 1-hour chart. Source: TradingView_

Bitcoin volatility cools into FOMC
----------------------------------

Data from [Cointelegraph Markets Pro](https://subscription.cointelegraph.com/) and [TradingView](https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCGBP/?exchange=BINANCE) followed skittish BTC price action hours after new lows of $56,500 on Bitstamp.

Traders remained on edge across risk assets ahead of the Federal Reserve’s next interest rates announcement and subsequent press conference from Chair Jerome Powell.

After the Quarterly Refunding Announcement, or QRA, [dealt a blow to the U.S. liquidity outlook](https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-price-loses-60k-support-2-month-lows), market participants hoped that Powell’s tone after the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting would not lean too hawkish.

“The FOMC statement and Powell presser this afternoon are likely to confirm USD money market pricing of a much more tepid policy normalization cycle,” Darius Dale, founder and CEO of risk management firm 42 Macro, [wrote](https://twitter.com/DariusDale42/status/1785617419169329344) in part of a digest on X (formerly Twitter).

&gt; “As much as Chair Powell would prefer to play up ‘two-sided risks to the economic outlook’, the reality is the preponderance of evidence supports the ‘no landing’ scenario as the highest probability outcome. As such, ‘higher for longer’ is likely to be the dominant message today.”

![Image 2](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/bb328ded-c405-4408-bb6e-2a1da087efec.png)

Fed target ra

The latest data from CME Group’s [FedWatch Tool](https://www.cmegroup.com/markets/interest-rates/cme-fedwatch-tool.html) underscored the lackluster expectations for good news, with the odds of the Fed holding rates at their current levels at 99%.

Striking a more optimistic tone, popular trader CrypNuevo suggested that the worst Bitcoin and altcoin losses were likely complete.

“BTC really dropped hard and this reinforces the idea that whatever Jerome Powell has to say today, it's likely priced-in,” he [told](https://twitter.com/CrypNuevo/status/1785659617122349256/photo/1) X subscribers.

“Will we get a retest of the range lows?”

![Image 3](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/d783e5be-af62-4d89-8f50-8b87f2bb0368.jpeg)

_BTC/USD annotated chart. Source: CrypNuevo/X_

In the latest edition of its London &amp; New York Daily Color market updates sent to Telegram channel subscribers, meanwhile, trading firm QCP Capital referenced both Powell and the QRA as potentially holding surprises for risk-on sentiment.

“There are two important events happening today that could either exacerbate this bearish move or reverse it,” it stated.

&gt; “Firstly, if Powell is dovish at FOMC, it could provide a bullish flip. Secondly, if the QRA (Quarterly Refunding Announcement) sees heavy issuances in US bills (front-end) instead of the 10-year (back-end) it would reduce fears of longer-term rates spiking and might put some brakes on the USD rally.”

BTC price in "typical" bull market retrace
------------------------------------------

Bitcoin traders thus eyed important BTC price levels to watch after multiple lines in the sand fell through.

**_Related: [Why is Bitcoin price down today?](https://cointelegraph.com/news/why-is-bitcoin-price-down-today)_**

“This current Bitcoin retrace is slowly turning into an almost 50-day retrace,” popular trader and analyst Rekt Capital [revealed](https://twitter.com/rektcapital/status/1785662534487245112/photo/1) on the day.

An accompanying chart compared BTC price pullbacks throughout the bull market which began in early 2023.

Rekt Capital described the latest downside move, coming in at over 20%, as “typical” within this context.

“Typical retraces have been 2-3 weeks, longer ones up to 2 months,” he noted.

![Image 4](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/33d728cb-eaff-4556-aa8c-1cef479543fb.jpeg)

_BTC/USD pullback comparison. Source: Rekt Capital/X_

Filbfilb, co-founder of trading suite DecenTrader, meanwhile forecast a possible Bitcoin renaissance following in the footsteps of gold in recent years.

“I think we can go lower than on that chart, but if its bullish over the next months it might happen like this as a general idea,” he wrote in an [X thread](https://twitter.com/filbfilb/status/1785645939149193222) while comparing the two assets.

![Image 5](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/682d6e73-daa7-4f12-aba2-fc68b39d496b.jpeg)

_BTC/USD vs. gold futures. Source: Filbfilb/X_

This article does not contain investment advice or recommendations. Every investment and trading move involves risk, and readers should conduct their own research when making a decision.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 14:46:27 GMT</pubDate><link>https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-price-bouncing-57k-why-these-levels-key</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: As CZ Gets His Sentence, Michael Lewis Should Rewatch 'Star Wars'

URL Source: https://www.coindesk.com/consensus-magazine/2024/05/01/as-cz-gets-his-sentence-michael-lewis-should-rewatch-star-wars/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:08:48.053Z

Markdown Content:
Author Michael Lewis tends to take a very charitable stance regarding Sam Bankman-Fried despite his recent conviction, which led to a [25-year prison sentence](https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2024/03/28/sam-bankman-fried-ftx-sentencing/).

Following publication last year of "Going Infinite," Lewis' book about the FTX founder that many said is over-generous, a Time magazine journalist [asked him](https://time.com/6321668/michael-lewis-sam-bankman-fried-going-infinite/) about [criticisms](https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/02/books/review/going-infinite-michael-lewis.html). "This is what happens when you address a mob," he said.

When movie rights for the book were shopped around Hollywood, the pitch letter said, as [reported](https://www.coindesk.com/business/2022/11/14/big-short-author-michael-lewis-spent-months-with-ftxs-sam-bankman-fried-and-is-writing-a-book/) in 2022, that Lewis "likens \[SBF and Binance's Changpeng "CZ" Zhao\] to the Luke Skywalker and Darth Vader of crypto" – and it wasn't hard to deduce that SBF was, in the "Big Short" author's view, the good guy and CZ the bad guy. SBF got a quarter century in prison. CZ was [just sentenced to four months](https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2024/04/30/binance-founder-changpeng-zhao-to-appear-in-court-today-for-sentencing/), and the judge, when explaining why he wasn't harsher on the former Binance CEO, said, "Everything I see about you and your characteristics are of a mitigating nature." Also: "There's no evidence that the defendant was ever informed" of illegal activity at Binance, the judge said.

Contrast that with what a judge told SBF when [deciding](https://www.coindesk.com/policy/2024/03/28/sam-bankman-fried-ftx-sentencing/) the length of his prison stay: "The scale of his crimes is measured not just by the amount of money that was stolen, but by the extraordinary harm caused to victims, who in some cases had their life savings wiped out overnight." Also, SBF never offered "a word of remorse for commission of terrible crimes."

Meanwhile, CZ stepped up, according to his judge: "The court finds the defendant has accepted responsibility."

SBF was found guilty of stealing billions of dollars from customers of the FTX cryptocurrency exchange. CZ pleaded guilty to violating the Bank Secrecy Act. Wrongdoing in both cases, but on completely different scales (though Binance did agree to pay a multi-billion-dollar fine.)

Lewis sold a lot of copies of his book, and a movie is [apparently being made](https://theankler.com/p/inside-hollywoods-sbf-mad-scramble-c04) via Apple. But he might want to watch "Star Wars" to remind himself who's who, if the U.S. legal system is any judge of character, anyway.

Edited by Benjamin Schiller.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 14:46:56 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.coindesk.com/consensus-magazine/2024/05/01/as-cz-gets-his-sentence-michael-lewis-should-rewatch-star-wars/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Your browser is up to date

URL Source: https://www.youtube.com/supported_browsers?next_url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtPHnNpHHxc

Markdown Content:
You can use YouTube's latest features!

*   [![Image 1: a red circle with an arrow in it](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/opera.png)

### Opera

](https://www.opera.com/)
*   [![Image 2: the firefox logo on a black background](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/firefox.png)

### Mozilla Firefox

](https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/new/?utm_source=youtube.com&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=supported-browser)
*   [![Image 3: the chrome logo on a black background](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/chrome.png)

### Google Chrome

](https://www.google.com/chrome/index.html?brand=CHNY&amp;utm_campaign=en&amp;utm_source=en-et-youtube&amp;utm_medium=et)
*   [![Image 4: a blue and green ea logo on a black background](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/edgium.png)

### Microsoft Edge

](https://www.microsoft.com/edge)

[Browse YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtPHnNpHHxc)
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 14:47:19 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/supported_browsers?next_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DUtPHnNpHHxc</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: BlackRock doubles down on tokenization via investment in Securitize

URL Source: https://blockworks.co/news/blackrock-tokenization-investment

Markdown Content:
1.  [home](https://blockworks.co/)
2.  [news](https://blockworks.co/news)
3.  [Business](https://blockworks.co/category/business)

The world’s largest asset manager led a $47 million funding round by a blockchain-focused firm it has worked with before

![Image 1: article-image](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblockworks-co.imgix.net%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2024%2F05%2Fblackrock.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=75)

Tada Images/Shutterstock modified by Blockworks

The world’s largest asset manager appears poised to move deeper into the tokenization space after injecting capital into a tokenization firm it has worked with before.

BlackRock led a $47 million funding round for Securitize, a company focused on bringing physical and traditional financial assets onto the blockchain, the firms said Wednesday. 

Fintech companies and [traditional finance giants have increasingly been testing out tokenization](https://blockworks.co/news/citibank-explores-tokenization-wisdomtree), noting that blockchain rails can help reduce costs and improve transparency. BlackRock Larry Fink has called tokenized securities “the next generation for markets.” 

To that end, [BlackRock](https://blockworks.co/tag/blackrock) and Securitize are not strangers. 

BlackRock launched its first tokenized fund — the BlackRock USD Institutional Digital Liquidity Fund — in March, offering a different way to earn US dollar yields. Qualified investors can subscribe to that fund through Securitize Markets.

**Read more:** [Circle debuts way to trade BlackRock tokenized fund shares for USDC](https://blockworks.co/news/blackrock-tokenized-fund-trading-circle-usdc)

“We believe that [tokenization](https://blockworks.co/tag/tokenization) has the potential to drive a significant transformation in capital markets infrastructure,” Joseph Chalom, BlackRock’s global head of strategic ecosystem partnerships, said in a statement. “Our investment in Securitize is another step in the evolution of our digital assets strategy.”  

Chalom is now a member of Securitize’s board of directors.

Other investors in the $47 million funding round include Hamilton Lane, ParaFi Capital and Tradeweb Markets. 

Private markets investment firm Hamilton Lane in January 2023 made [available](https://securitize.io/learn/press/hamilton-lane-fund-securitize-polygon) one of its equity funds through a Securitize feeder fund tokenized on Polygon. 

* * *

**Start your day with top crypto insights from David Canellis and Katherine Ross. [Subscribe to the Empire newsletter](https://blockworks.co/newsletter/empire).**

Tags

*   [BlackRock](https://blockworks.co/tag/blackrock)
*   [Tokenization](https://blockworks.co/tag/tokenization)
*   [TradFi](https://blockworks.co/tag/tradfi)

WED - FRI, OCTOBER 9 - 11, 2024

Pack your bags, anon — we’re heading west! Join us in the beautiful Salt Lake City for the third installment of Permissionless. Come for the alpha, stay for the fresh air. Permissionless III promises unforgettable panels, killer networking opportunities, and mountains \[…\] [![Image 2: Research report HL cover.jpg](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fimpressive-horses-5641a8b530.media.strapiapp.com%2FResearch_report_HL_cover_bfad536ba8.jpg&amp;w=1920&amp;q=20)](https://app.blockworksresearch.com/research/hyperliquid-deep-dive)

Research

It's increasingly apparent that orderbooks represent the most efficient model for perpetual trading, with the primary obstacle being that the most popular blockchains are ill-suited for hosting a fully onchain orderbook. Hyperliquid is a perpetual trading protocol built on its own L1 that aims to replicate the user experience of centralized exchanges while offering a fully onchain orderbook.

[news](https://blockworks.co/news)
----------------------------------

Breaking headlines across our core coverage categories.

[![Image 3: article-image](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblockworks-co.imgix.net%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2024%2F04%2Fcz.jpg&amp;w=1536&amp;q=40)](https://blockworks.co/news/changpeng-zhao-sentencing-verdict)

The sentencing closes the book on the DOJ’s settlement with Binance and its former CEO

[![Image 4: article-image](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblockworks-co.imgix.net%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2024%2F04%2FRoger-Ver.jpg&amp;w=1536&amp;q=40)](https://blockworks.co/news/roger-ver-tax-fraud-charges)

Roger Ver was arrested in Spain on Tuesday, the DOJ said

[![Image 5: article-image](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblockworks-co.imgix.net%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2024%2F04%2FED_hacks_20231105a-2.jpg&amp;w=1536&amp;q=40)](https://blockworks.co/news/samourai-wallet-matters-memecoins-privacy)

This case is a big deal — so big, in fact, that one wonders whether the crypto community fully appreciates its gravity

[![Image 6: article-image](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblockworks-co.imgix.net%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2024%2F04%2Fcoinbase-light-purple.jpg&amp;w=1536&amp;q=40)](https://blockworks.co/news/coinbase-q1-earnings-results)

Higher trading volumes and stablecoin revenue are set to drive sizeable quarter-over-quarter improvements, analysts say

[![Image 7: article-image](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblockworks-co.imgix.net%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2024%2F04%2Fjerome.jpg&amp;w=1536&amp;q=40)](https://blockworks.co/news/crypto-slides-ahead-of-fed-rate-decision)

Bitcoin and ether lost around 3% and 5% over 24-hours, respectively, erasing Monday’s gains, after the first day of spot ETF trading in Hong Kong left much to be desired

[![Image 8: article-image](https://blockworks.co/_next/image?url=https%3A%2F%2Fblockworks-co.imgix.net%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2024%2F04%2Feigenlayer-screenshot.jpg&amp;w=1536&amp;q=40)](https://blockworks.co/news/empire-newsletter-eigenlayer-airdrop-criticisms)

There’s some truth to the EIGEN concerns popping up on Crypto Twitter
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 14:47:43 GMT</pubDate><link>https://blockworks.co/news/blackrock-tokenization-investment</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: This Analyst Says You Should Sell Your BTC in May and Go Away

URL Source: https://cryptopotato.com/this-analyst-says-you-should-sell-your-btc-in-may-and-go-away/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:22:54+00:00

Markdown Content:
Nic Puckrin, the co-founder and CEO of crypto information portal Coin Bureau, thinks selling one’s bitcoins (BTC) in May would be more profitable than offloading the assets in September.

According to his [tweet](https://x.com/nicrypto/status/1785607112682246286), the cumulative returns of disposing of one’s cryptocurrencies in May have surpassed selling in September or any other time of the year by over 1000%.

Puckrin explained that the phrase “Sell in May, Go Away” is from the traditional finance space and refers to the effect of seasonality. The adage dates back centuries and postulates that the best six months of the year for stocks are recorded from November through April, suggesting that investors should sell in May and wait until October to buy again.

The saying may apply to the crypto sector because in the past five years, buying BTC in October and selling in April has accrued cumulative returns of 1,449% compared to buying in May and selling in September, which had a negative return of -29%.

Puckrin [cited](https://x.com/nicrypto/status/1785607835872575683) a report by cryptocurrency research firm K33 to substantiate his claims, insisting that other studies have shown similar results for the same strategy. Hence, the Coin Bureau CEO believes crypto investors would have realized more profits if they sold their assets last month, especially after BTC rallied to $73,700 for the first time in mid-March and traded around $70,000 for the remainder of the month.

[![Image 1: blockdrop unlocking bitcoin mining for everyone claim your airdrop](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4150113)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=183000&amp;plid=2399417&amp;setID=631314&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=880818&amp;banID=521892882&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2317939&amp;adSize=300x250&amp;mt=1714577645889480&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fcryptopotato.com%2Fthis-analyst-says-you-should-sell-your-btc-in-may-and-go-away%2F&amp;hc=6fb4fb704d2c1dbf04d0a724e09147446cecd6a3&amp;location=)

Market Sentiment is Cooling
---------------------------

On-chain indicators and macroeconomic conditions suggest it may be too late for investors to sell their assets now, seeing that May has gotten off to a bad start and market sentiment has started cooling.

The Bitcoin Fear and Greed Index [shows](https://cryptopotato.com/crypto-investor-sentiment-turns-neutral-as-btc-price-plummets-below-57k/) retail sentiment is waning as it is in neutral territory. Puckrin said Bitcoin search trends have declined, and X is full of doom posts.

Institutions also appear to be less bullish on crypto investment products, as seen in the U.S. spot Bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) market witnessing steady outflows for the past five consecutive trading days. Even the newly-launched ETFs in Hong Kong are [seeing](https://cryptopotato.com/disappointing-launch-day-for-hong-kongs-bitcoin-ethereum-etfs-as-btc-slumps-below-61k/) much lower inflows than analysts predicted.

In addition, Puckrin disclosed that perpetual funding rates have declined substantially, and the Chicago Mercantile Exchange futures open interest held by non-ETF funds have fallen to their lowest since October 2023.

Meanwhile, BTC has [fallen](https://cryptopotato.com/crypto-markets-lost-over-200b-as-btc-dumps-to-57k-ahead-of-fomc-meeting-market-watch/) more than 22% from its all-time high and was [changing hands](https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/bitcoin/) at $57,100 at the time of writing.

SPECIAL OFFER (Sponsored)

**LIMITED OFFER 2024 for CryptoPotato readers at Bybit: [Use this link](https://cryptopotato.com/pl/bybit24/) to register and open a $500 BTC-USDT position on Bybit Exchange for free!**

* * *
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:34:26 GMT</pubDate><link>https://cryptopotato.com/this-analyst-says-you-should-sell-your-btc-in-may-and-go-away/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Gold vs. Bitcoin: Expert predicts May prices for top assets

URL Source: https://finbold.com/gold-vs-bitcoin-expert-predicts-may-prices-for-top-assets/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:20:07+00:00

Markdown Content:
Though some experts, analysts, and marketers have been rhetorically placing [gold](https://finbold.com/guide/buy-gold-with-a-credit-card/) and [Bitcoin](https://finbold.com/guide/fastest-way-to-buy-bitcoin/) ([BTC](https://finbold.com/cryptocurrency/bitcoin/)) in the same category for years, they have seemingly diverged in significant ways in 2024. 

Indeed, while gold has been rising at an incredible pace as [economic and geopolitical concerns mount](https://finbold.com/how-putin-and-xi-are-secretly-fueling-golds-record-rally/), BTC’s [trading](https://finbold.com/guide/cryptocurrency-trading/) is more risk-off, with the most striking example coming at the height of the Israel-Iran war scare when fears seemingly outweighed the optimism stemming from the halving event.

Despite the world’s premier [cryptocurrency](https://finbold.com/cryptocurrencies/) seeing its highest month-end prices on record in March, _Bloomberg’s_ Senior Commodity Strategist Mike McGlone [opined](https://twitter.com/mikemcglone11/status/1785619729685582216) in a recent [X](https://finbold.com/guide/how-to-buy-x-stock/) post that gold has a substantial upper hand compared to Bitcoin – and, indeed, compared to the [S&amp;P 500](https://finbold.com/guide/how-to-buy-spy-stock/).

### Picks for you

BTC in particular, stands in contrast with gold as, after hitting a new all-time high in March, it saw a massive decline in April which, by May, saw it drop to [approximatelly $57,000](https://finbold.com/bitcoin-plummets-under-57000-as-crypto-market-faces-bear-market-reality/) – a level some experts [identified](https://finbold.com/boom-or-bust-experts-reveal-bitcoin-price-that-will-determine-its-fate/) as a crucial [support](https://finbold.com/guide/support-and-resistance/) zone – while the world’s top [commodity](https://finbold.com/guide/what-are-commodities/) ended the fourth month at its own record price.

Gains for gold and pain for Bitcoin
-----------------------------------

McGlone’s most recent analysis follows his previous assessments closely as he sees substantial volatility and arguably the anomalous performance of [stocks](https://finbold.com/stocks/) in a high [interest rate](https://finbold.com/guide/best-interest-rate-savings-accounts/) environment as some of the crucial headwinds for BTC and S&amp;P 500 and important tailwinds for gold and other commodities.

Additionally, stocks and cryptocurrencies may face trouble ahead in similar ways to commodities when they had to swallow a price cure resulting from a COVID-era price surge back in 2022 before reentering the more recent rally.

“A primary headwind for the S&amp;P 500 may be the high-price cure example that’s afflicted most commodities since 2022. It’s likely not a coincidence that #inflation has remained sticky and FederalReserve rate-cut risks have leaned toward hikes, on the back of the rapidly rising stock index closing at the 5,254 high in 1Q.”

![Image 1: a chart showing the price of gold and silver](https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/x9256HuteytSMDH4QnLCSBUBIK0q1wBU_D6XsdEQjV0eLydBqF7eHS5BhX41yGXth-e4aY20bkfg6mzpMwGID_XEvxe5ny51pvZyE8suXekGFWD_lOnlQk2pZwPKnsmVF2Hp8QUG4SHPqXi-XBYCZEc)

Crocodile’s jaw chart, BTC vs. gold vs. S&amp;P 500. Source: Bloomberg Intelligence

The expert also assessed that the increasingly hawkish rhetoric coming out of the FED is likely only to further emphasize the dynamic, which leans well into his previous forecast that gold is set to [surge toward $3,000](https://finbold.com/opportunity-gold-could-reach-3000-per-ounce/) per ounce this year.

Finally, McGlone also linked the likely upcoming fortunes of the wider [cryptocurrency market](https://finbold.com/category/cryptocurrency-news/) to the apparent slowdown that is affecting the [stock market](https://finbold.com/category/stocks-news/) and its major [indices](https://finbold.com/guide/how-to-trade-indices/) and explained it might struggle to maintain momentum should the S&amp;P 500 truly end its “almost straight up rally’ – a scenario he judged likely with [recent recessionary forecasts](https://finbold.com/us-recession-is-delayed-but-still-coming-warns-chief-strategist/) – that started after they hit October 2023 lows.

Still, it is noteworthy that the macro strategist’s forecasts – when it comes to cryptocurrencies at least – haven’t historically been the most accurate given that he [forecast trouble ahead](https://finbold.com/crypto-recession-alert-mike-mcglone-signals-troubles-ahead/) for the crypto markets less than a month before they entered into a major rally.

[_Buy stocks now with eToro – trusted and advanced investment platform_](https://visit.finbold.com/etoro)

**_Disclaimer_**_: The content on this site should not be considered investment advice. Investing is speculative. When investing, your capital is at risk._
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:35:11 GMT</pubDate><link>https://finbold.com/gold-vs-bitcoin-expert-predicts-may-prices-for-top-assets/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: FanSociety creator explains how NFTs can bring musicians and fans together

URL Source: https://cointelegraph.com/news/fansociety-web3-nfts-musicians-fans-together-decentralization

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:20:00.000Z

Markdown Content:
Fans want to journey alongside their favorite musicians as they explore their creativity and expand their catalog. FanSociety hopes to be the Web3 platform that makes this possible.

213 Total views

22 Total shares

![Image 1: FanSociety creator explains how NFTs can bring musicians and fans together](https://images.cointelegraph.com/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=90,width=1434/https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/dd6fedee-2c4c-4ee6-8339-211eb45948c6.jpg)

Own this piece of crypto history

[Collect this article as NFT](https://mint.cointelegraph.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcointelegraph.com%2Fnews%2Ffansociety-web3-nfts-musicians-fans-together-decentralization&amp;utm_source=cointelegraph_com&amp;utm_medium=button&amp;utm_campaign=articles)

[Nonfungible tokens, or NFTs](https://cointelegraph.com/learn/what-are-nfts-and-why-are-they-revolutionizing-the-art-world), took the world by storm in 2019 — and then eroded to near rubble as the entire crypto market contracted and the industry fell into a nearly two-year-long bear market. An objective assessment of the NFT phenomena might conclude that the technology did deliver on a good deal of its promises, and instead of writing off the failed projects as scams, it might be more insightful to take a closer look at what features were needed to make projects successful. 

On Episode 35 of _The Agenda_ podcast, hosts Ray Salmond and Jonathan DeYoung spoke with Miles, a Web3 developer who is the creative mind behind FanSociety — a funding mechanism for musicians that borrows and blends ideas from traditional fan clubs of the 1950s with modern crowdfunding ideas and immutable storage on blockchain networks.

Tech should be adaptable and give users room to grow
----------------------------------------------------

Any aspiring musician knows that securing funding for an album is difficult, and of course, once the album is out, locking in fans for life becomes the next hurdle. Miles explained that he envisions FanSociety being used as a tool for [creators to connect with their audience](https://cointelegraph.com/magazine/singer-verites-web3-music-nfts-community/), reward loyalty and grow in a way that is more organic than the typical NFT collections that currently exist.

He also explained that FanSociety has the dual purpose of allowing musicians to [raise money from fans](https://cointelegraph.com/news/music-nfts-are-helping-independent-creators-monetize-and-build-a-fanbase) while also rewarding and retaining them by giving them digital artifacts as part of their expanding discography.

According to Miles, a recurring issue with NFT collections is that projects often have fixed sizes and creators need to issue a new contract to “extend” the collection:

&gt; “It doesn’t make sense to have a limit, you know, and kind of just have one smart contract. And, like I said, it’s like a boolean. You either have the token, you either have the NFT or you don’t. And a lot of what was going on as well was very successful musicians were launching NFT projects, and it was kind of that same situation where, you know, they’ve only got 10,000 NFTs available, and you either have one or you don’t. And to me, that’s very elitist and kind of antithetical to kind of the whole Web3 ethos, to me. And so I wanted to do something different.”

**_Related:_** [**_NFT utility continues to captivate fashion and luxury brands — NFT Paris_**](https://cointelegraph.com/news/nft-captivate-fashion-luxury-nft-paris)

Fan engagement should also have value
-------------------------------------

Revenue sharing is another issue FanSociety aims to tackle. Miles lamented that popular streaming platforms and record labels only give creators a sliver of the revenue generated by their music and that platforms tend to absorb the bulk of tips that creators receive from fans:

&gt; “You look at Twitch, for example. You tip somebody, you give them money, you subscribe to them. First of all, the platform takes 50% rev\[enue\] split, which is atrocious to me. And we don’t know if that’s going to go up in the future, right? The content creators on there don’t know if that’s going to go up to 60%, 70%, if they’re going to throw more fees on top of that. So there’s that kind of problem.” For artists who will use the platform to expand their catalog and engage with fans, Miles said the NFTs can be a [more meaningful show of appreciation](https://cointelegraph.com/news/music-nfts-a-powerful-tool-to-transform-an-audience-into-a-community) than “a sticker pack to put in their chat” or something else that is kind of gimmicky and “not very valuable.”

Miles said:

&gt; “I’d like to see more value being able to be given back to the supporters, and so that’s what I’m trying to support. And it’s up to the artist to decide what sorts of things, what sorts of ways they want to show their appreciation to people who support them.”

To hear more from Mile’s conversation with _The Agenda_ — including his future plans for FanSociety — listen to the full episode on [Cointelegraph’s Podcasts page](https://cointelegraph.com/podcasts/the-agenda), [Apple Podcasts](https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-agenda/id1659393166) or [Spotify](https://open.spotify.com/show/6azmkkIXj5LQbxTRAbAqXS). And don’t forget to check out Cointelegraph’s [full lineup](https://cointelegraph.com/podcasts) of other shows!

**_Magazine:_** [**_Get Bitcoin or die tryin’: Why hip hop stars love crypto_**](https://cointelegraph.com/magazine/get-bitcoin-or-die-tryin-why-hip-hop-stars-love-crypto/)

This article is for general information purposes and is not intended to be and should not be taken as legal or investment advice. The views, thoughts, and opinions expressed here are the author’s alone and do not necessarily reflect or represent the views and opinions of Cointelegraph.

Explore more articles like this

Subscribe to the Nifty Newsletter

![Image 2](https://images.cointelegraph.com/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=90,width=96/https://s3.cointelegraph.com/storage/uploads/view/0d86bc4aa7062cddf58cfe6c84268e02.svg)

Your go-to source for staying on top of market trends, and emerging artists, and unlocking opportunities in the NFT landscape. Delivered every Wednesday

![Image 3](https://zoa.cointelegraph.com/pixel?postId=129086&amp;regionId=1)
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:35:36 GMT</pubDate><link>https://cointelegraph.com/news/fansociety-web3-nfts-musicians-fans-together-decentralization</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Witness Chain Soars Past $5B In Delegated ETH Amid Polygon DePIN Push

URL Source: https://thedefiant.io/news/defi/witness-chain-soars-past-usd5b-in-delegated-eth-amid-polygon-depin-push

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:17:00.000Z

Markdown Content:
Witness Chain is the third-largest AVS on EigenLayer with 1.82 million staked Ether delegated.

Witness Chain, a proof system for decentralized physical infrastructure (DePIN) networks, has attracted more than $5 billion worth of delegated stake from EigenLayer restakers.

Witness Chain [announced](https://twitter.com/witnesschain/status/1784958502630510636) the milestone via tweet on April 29. With the project now secured by 1.82 million ETH worth $5.24 billion, Witness Chain ranks as the [third largest](https://www.stakingrewards.com/assets/actively-validated-service?sort=restaking_marketcap&amp;timeframe=7d&amp;order=desc&amp;byChange=false) Actively Validated Service (AVS) on EigenLayer behind Eigen DA with $7.79 billion and Eoracle with $5.36 billion, according to Staking Rewards.

“Thanks to our wonderful community, we've surpassed $5B+ in restaked ETH,“ Witness Chain [tweeted](https://twitter.com/witnesschain/status/1784958502630510636). “Big hug to all 16,677 stakers, 53 operators, and LRTs for embarking on this journey to unify DePIN economies.”

Witness Chain is one of nine AVSs that are currently live on EigenLayer. EigenLayer, the pioneering Ethereum restaking protocol, allows Ethereum stakers to secure third-party [AVSs](https://thedefiant.io/news/defi/eigenlayer-launches-six-actively-validated-services) to earn additional yield on top of staking rewards.

DePIN Ecosystem
---------------

According to Ankr, a blockchain infrastructure provider and Witness Chain node operator, Witness Chain serves to unify the siloed [DePIN economy](https://thedefiant.io/news/defi/depin-sector-sees-resurgence-in-2024).

“Through Witness Chain, a shared economy of integrated physical assets is unlocked, facilitating the exchange of resources like computing power, communication, energy, \[and\] storage,” Ankr [said](https://www.ankr.com/blog/ankr-and-witness-chain-team-up-for-de-pin-and-avs-innovation/). “Witness Chain enables DePIN projects to share info about their physical locations, network capabilities, and more. This will allow dePINs to connect with each other, establishing an end-to-end supply chain of decentralized infrastructure.”

Witness Chain provides “Watchtower” nodes that function as independent auditors for DePIN networks.

The project offers several key services including Proof of Diligence — which verifies that Layer 2 transactions are executed correctly, Proof of Location — which verifies the physical location of DePIN infrastructure, Proof of Bandwidth — which verifies the network bandwidth available to DePIN projects, and a DePIN “Coordination Layer.”

Ankr said Witness Chain’s architecture enables the development of new applications on top of the shared DePIN ecosystem.

“By enabling DePIN projects to share information like location and capacity, watchtowers help create an interconnected ecosystem,” Ankr said. “Once two physically separated pieces of infrastructure recognize each other’s locations and can ensure enough connectivity, they can communicate with each other to exchange value, drive demand, enhance reliability, and reduce redundancy.”

Polygon’s DePIN push
--------------------

Witness Chain was built using Polygon’s Chain Development Kit (CDK) and is among a growing list of Polygon-based DePIN projects enjoying significant growth.

On April 25, Dimo, a Polygon-based DePIN project allowing vehicle owners to collect and monetize data from their vehicles, [celebrated](https://twitter.com/DIMO_Network/status/1783495083511153052) that it had onboarded 80,000 vehicles within its network.

On April 30 and May 1, PowerPod, a Polygon-based DePIN network connecting electric vehicles, charging stations, and energy storage, [attended](https://twitter.com/PowerPod_People/status/1784873223982551210) the Mobility Live ME event in Abu Dhabi.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:35:57 GMT</pubDate><link>https://thedefiant.io/news/defi/witness-chain-soars-past-usd5b-in-delegated-eth-amid-polygon-depin-push</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Your browser is up to date

URL Source: https://www.youtube.com/supported_browsers?next_url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jq0VDuLD9oQ

Markdown Content:
You can use YouTube's latest features!

*   [![Image 1: the chrome logo on a black background](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/chrome.png)

### Google Chrome

](https://www.google.com/chrome/index.html?brand=CHNY&amp;utm_campaign=en&amp;utm_source=en-et-youtube&amp;utm_medium=et)
*   [![Image 2: a red circle with an arrow in it](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/opera.png)

### Opera

](https://www.opera.com/)
*   [![Image 3: the firefox logo on a black background](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/firefox.png)

### Mozilla Firefox

](https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/new/?utm_source=youtube.com&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=supported-browser)
*   [![Image 4: a blue and green ea logo on a black background](https://www.youtube.com/img/desktop/supported_browsers/edgium.png)

### Microsoft Edge

](https://www.microsoft.com/edge)

[Browse YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jq0VDuLD9oQ)
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:37:13 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/supported_browsers?next_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3Djq0VDuLD9oQ</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: How To Opt Out Of The Fiat Economy

URL Source: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtPHnNpHHxc

Markdown Content:
0:00 / 3:21•Watch full video
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:37:50 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UtPHnNpHHxc</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: What's next for Binance founder CZ after his 4-month sentence?

URL Source: https://ambcrypto.com/whats-next-for-binance-founder-cz-after-his-4-month-sentence/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:00:26+00:00

Markdown Content:
![Image 1: What's next for Binance founder CZ after his 4-month sentence?](data:image/svg+xml,%3Csvg%20xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg'%20viewBox='0%200%201200%20686'%3E%3C/svg%3E)

*   _CZ is ready to do his time and move on to the next phase of life._
*    _Market watchers view Binance founder’s sentence as a “great deal.”_

[Binance \[BNB\]](https://ambcrypto.com/category/binance-news/) founder and former CEO Changpeng Zhao, commonly known as “CZ,” commented on his four-month [sentence](https://ambcrypto.com/crypto-billionaire-cz-sentenced-to-four-months-in-prison/) by the Seattle court on the 30th of April. 

Reacting to the sentence on X (formerly Twitter), CZ extended gratitude for the overwhelming support received during the trial and [said](https://twitter.com/cz_binance/status/1785465555899822488), 

&gt; “I will do my time, conclude this phase, and focus on the next chapter of my life (education).”

Last November, CZ pleaded guilty to violating U.S. money laundering regulations. Binance, the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange, paid $4.3 billion as part of the plea deal. 

Additionally, CZ paid $50 million in fines in the plea deal. However, market watchers viewed the fine as pale compared to his net worth of over $40 billion. 

#### Market reaction, what’s next for Binance founder?

Some claimed that the four-month sentence is a great deal considering prosecutors proposed a three-year sentence. 

Compared to the 25-year sentence given to FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried, CZ’s look like a tiny blip. 

One of the market watchers, Autism Capital, [claimed](https://twitter.com/AutismCapital/status/1785407636940452339), 

&gt; “CZ really is the best to ever do it. Unlike Sam, he didn’t lose anyone’s money. He is still a hero to all. He literally memed his  prison sentence into existence. He does 4 months in the easiest camp prison playing pickleball and meditating. Walks away with $47 billion dollars”

Bloomberg analyst James Seyffart also acknowledged that CZ got a great deal and [quipped](https://twitter.com/JSeyff/status/1785395300229607541), 

&gt; “4 months for $40B in gains? $10B per month doesn’t sound too bad. I’d take that trade.  
&gt; I’d take that trade, too.”

The four-month sentence means CZ will be out by Q4 2024. In March, CZ revealed his new education project, Giggle Academy. 

The project aims to grant free education access to children and will be his main focus when he finishes the sentence. 

However, the former Binance chief reiterated that he will continue being a passive investor in crypto. 

&gt; “I will remain a passive investor (and holder) in crypto. Our industry has entered a new phase. Compliance is super important. A silver lining of this whole process is that Binance has been under the microscope. And funds are SAFU.”

In the meantime, the BNB token was down 9% in the past 24 hours. But its price remained above $500, which has been a key psychological support since March.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:38:11 GMT</pubDate><link>https://ambcrypto.com/whats-next-for-binance-founder-cz-after-his-4-month-sentence/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Bitcoin Milestone Ahead? Analyst Forecasts New Peak This Month

URL Source: https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-milestone-ahead-analyst-forecasts-new-peak-this-month/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:00:15Z

Markdown Content:
[![Image 1](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=3803600)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2059551&amp;setID=579130&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=753612&amp;banID=520989383&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=1985507&amp;adSize=150x45&amp;mt=1714577892577850&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fnews%2Fbitcoin%2Fbitcoin-milestone-ahead-analyst-forecasts-new-peak-this-month%2F&amp;hc=c6e9620a1b907453ddcdfdef54b511e00a9ff76a&amp;location=)

In the face of a general market decline and pessimism, Captain Faibik, a cryptocurrency expert and enthusiast, has emerged with an optimistic outlook for [Bitcoin](https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-profit-crunch-hash-price-hits-record-low-post-halving-whats-next-for-miners/) (BTC) foreseeable future trajectory, predicting that the crypto asset could rise to a new all-time high before this current month closes. 

Bitcoin To Reach New All-Time High In May
-----------------------------------------

Faibik’s [analysis](https://x.com/CryptoFaibik/status/1785515818853265455), which is based on his in-depth knowledge of cryptocurrency dynamics and a sharp eye for market trends, explores the possibility of a large short-term rise in Bitcoin. According to the analyst, Bitcoin is at a key junction currently testing the daily Moving Average 100 (MA100) level once more after recovering from it in the past.

![Image 2: Bitcoin](https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Captain-Faibik-Bitcoin-Chart.jpg?w=460&amp;resize=460%2C220)

Potential for a new peak in May | Source: Captain Faibik on X

Historically, the crypto asset has found considerable support at the 100MA level. Should [BTC](https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/spot-bitcoin-etfs-outflows/) recover from this point on, Captain Faibik anticipates a significant rise on the upside in the upcoming days. Thus, he expects the digital asset to reach a new all-time high within the month.

![Image 3](https://servedbyadbutler.com/error/blank.gif)

[![Image 4: a gold and black poker chip with the words huge get bonus](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4118444)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2374568&amp;setID=366606&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=873125&amp;banID=521839794&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2293217&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714577892582984&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fnews%2Fbitcoin%2Fbitcoin-milestone-ahead-analyst-forecasts-new-peak-this-month%2F&amp;hc=9136ba614e20c27d9b1d97ce2f9ffb7b79889b7e&amp;location=)

The post read:

&gt; Last time, BTC bounced back from the daily MA100, and now it is testing it again. If it bounces back from here, we can expect a Bullish Rally in the coming days. New All the High could be incoming this month

The crypto analyst noted Bitcoin’s price action in the daily timeframe also suggests that a bullish rise is on the horizon. Faibik stated that on the daily timeframe chart, BTC is still moving above the major trendline and inside the green box indicated in his chart. As a result, the analyst expects BTC to undergo a quick comeback.

Related Reading: [If History Repeats, This Is How Bitcoin Price Will Perform In The Next 6 Months](https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/if-history-rhymes-bitcoin-price-next-6-months/)

[![Image 5: a gold and black poker chip with the words huge get bonus](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4118444)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2374569&amp;setID=452518&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=873125&amp;banID=521839794&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2293218&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714577892586133&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fnews%2Fbitcoin%2Fbitcoin-milestone-ahead-analyst-forecasts-new-peak-this-month%2F&amp;hc=cba0f6151260fc92062df966cef410163c19a7db&amp;location=)

Another notable finding from Captain Faibik is that the daily Relative Strength Index (RSI) has been drifting below a trendline that has been in place for some months. Although this might indicate a brief waning of positive momentum, Faibik interprets it as a sign of an impending price recovery for Bitcoin. Given that BTC is still moving inside the bullish flag pattern, the expert anticipates a [bounce back](https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/btc/bitcoin-price-bounces-back-64500/) towards $68,000 in the upcoming days.

$100,000 Price Target For BTC
-----------------------------

Captain Faibik’s most bullish target for BTC recently is the $100,000 price mark. Last week, Faibik [pointed out](https://x.com/CryptoFaibik/status/1782607799559627136) key narratives that could catalyze Bitcoin’s price to $100,000 in the coming months.

Furthermore, Faibik highlighted that BTC Bulls have solidly secured the weekly Exponential Moving Average (EMA) 10 following the October 2017 Descending Channel breakout. Due to this, the crypto analyst is setting $100,000 as the digital asset’s next price target.

[![Image 6: a gold and black poker chip with the words huge get bonus](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4118444)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2374570&amp;setID=452519&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=873125&amp;banID=521839794&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2293220&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714577892762904&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fnews%2Fbitcoin%2Fbitcoin-milestone-ahead-analyst-forecasts-new-peak-this-month%2F&amp;hc=aeb79834cca6754de434ad14ef857229fba900c9&amp;location=)

Following a decrease of more than 13% over the previous 7 days, the price of Bitcoin is currently trading at $57,701. In the last day, its market cap has plummeted by over 6%, while its trading volume has increased by about 61%.

![Image 7: Bitcoin](https://www.tradingview.com/x/DFYWzTQM/)

BTC trading at $57,690 on the 1D chart | Source: BTCUSDT on [Tradingview.com](https://www.tradingview.com/x/DFYWzTQM/)

Featured image from iStock, chart from Tradingview.com

Disclaimer: The article is provided for educational purposes only. It does not represent the opinions of NewsBTC on whether to buy, sell or hold any investments and naturally investing carries risks. You are advised to conduct your own research before making any investment decisions. Use information provided on this website entirely at your own risk.

![Image 8](https://servedbyadbutler.com/error/blank.gif)

[![Image 9: a banner with the words'bitstarz' and an image of a woman in a red dress](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=898067)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=1897423&amp;setID=533110&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=378944&amp;banID=519875620&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=1827587&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714577892948801&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fnews%2Fbitcoin%2Fbitcoin-milestone-ahead-analyst-forecasts-new-peak-this-month%2F&amp;hc=83eb0fe240257ab49b6ef09912986c3d30fbc989&amp;location=)

![Image 10: Godspower Owie](https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/WhatsApp-Image-2023-11-01-at-10.59.20-AM.jpeg?resize=200%2C200)

My name is Godspower Owie and i am an employee for Bitcoinnist and NewsBTC news outlet. Sometimes i like to picture myself as an explorer, this is because i like visiting new places, i like learning new things (useful things to be precise), i like meeting new people - people who makes an impact in my life no matter how little it is. I cherish my time, my work, my family, and loved ones. I mean, those are probably the most important things in anyone's life. I don't chase illusions, i chase dreams.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:38:34 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin/bitcoin-milestone-ahead-analyst-forecasts-new-peak-this-month/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Dogecoin’s Co-creator Billy Markus’ Remarks on Cryptocurrency Market Decline

URL Source: https://coinedition.com/dogecoins-co-creator-billy-markus-remarks-on-cryptocurrency-market-decline/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:00:00+00:00

Markdown Content:
Published: May 1, 2024

Last Updated: May 1, 2024

*   **Billy Markus, co-creator of Dogecoin, expressed doubt about crypto trading during the market crash.**
*   **Markus’s remarks highlighted the crypto market’s decline.**
*   **Market experts have attributed several factors to this downturn.**

Billy Markus, co-creator of Dogecoin, has commented on the current downtrend witnessed by the crypto market. Markus is a crypto influencer with a large following of 2.1 million on X. He uses the pseudonym Shibetoshi Nakamoto and often shares memes and views on various topics, including politics, finance, and cryptocurrency. 

Following the dip of digital assets due to the current crypto market crash, the co-creator expressed doubt over crypto trading, [saying](https://x.com/BillyM2k/status/1785316776735383950), _“Man, crypto sure does suck.”_ 

Markus’s remarks highlighted the crypto market’s decline, led by the plummeting prices of Bitcoin and Ethereum. Over the past intraday session, Bitcoin slipped by 5.69%, trading at $57,762 during press time. 

Ethereum, the second-largest cryptocurrency, lost 3.87% of its value during the same period, reaching $2,894. Meanwhile, Dogecoin, created as a light-hearted parody of Bitcoin, dipped 8%, slipping from $0.1458 to $0.1252. 

Market experts have attributed several factors to this downturn, including Binance founder CZ’s four-month prison sentence for violating the Bank Secrecy Act and money laundering charges. 

In addition, disappointing job reports and the underwhelming performance of Bitcoin-Ethereum exchange-traded funds (ETFs) in Hong Kong are said to have fueled this current market outlook, as investors expected it to surpass the performance of U.S. ETFs.

Hong Kong-based ETFs have demonstrated a healthy trend, amassing $12.4 million through trading activities. Meanwhile, these funds have seen substantial inflows, totaling $141 million, directed towards Bitcoin and partially into Ethereum.

In comparison, the figure observed upon the launch of U.S. spot ETFs totaled $740 million in assets, with trading volume reaching $4.6 billion. This stark contrast reflects the robust uptake and enthusiasm surrounding U.S. ETF offerings compared to their Hong Kong counterparts.

Moreover, Markus’s tweet mirrors a broader sentiment within the community, where concerns about market volatility and regulatory scrutiny persist. As such, investors remain vigilant for possible changes in market trajectory amidst ongoing developments.

**_Disclaimer:_** _The information presented in this article is for informational and educational purposes only. The article does not constitute financial advice or advice of any kind. Coin Edition is not responsible for any losses incurred as a result of the utilization of content, products, or services mentioned. Readers are advised to exercise caution before taking any action related to the company._
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:39:00 GMT</pubDate><link>https://coinedition.com/dogecoins-co-creator-billy-markus-remarks-on-cryptocurrency-market-decline/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Billionaire Mike Novogratz Reacts to Roger Ver's Arrest

URL Source: https://u.today/billionaire-mike-novogratz-reacts-to-roger-vers-arrest

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:59:00+0000

Markdown Content:
The recent arrest of [Roger Ver,](https://u.today/breaking-bitcoin-jesus-roger-ver-arrested) an early Bitcoin investor, has shaken the cryptocurrency community. The U.S. Department of Justice accused Ver of mail fraud, tax evasion and filing fake returns to avoid paying at least $48 million in taxes.

Ver, who earned the moniker "Bitcoin Jesus" after spreading the word about Bitcoin in its early days, was arrested in Spain this weekend and might be extradited.

The allegations are the latest brought by U.S. authorities against prominent crypto entrepreneurs. Changpeng Zhao, cofounder of Binance, the world's largest crypto exchange, was sentenced to four months in jail on Tuesday. Sam Bankman-Fried, the former CEO of the FTX crypto exchange, received 25 years in prison.

The news of Ver's arrest has sent waves through the crypto community, provoking reactions from many, including Galaxy CEO and billionaire investor Mike Novogratz.

[Novogratz](https://twitter.com/novogratz/status/1785639426875375978) called Roger Ver's arrest a "sad one." U.S. authorities accuse Ver of failing to record capital gains and pay taxes on his Bitcoin holdings, which he began acquiring in 2011.

&gt; The Roger Ver story is a sad one. He didn’t/ doesn’t trust the US govt. Of course, if you served hard time for selling firecrackers over the internet you might not either. He renounced his citizenship soon after serving his time. He hired lawyers and filed the paperwork.…
&gt; 
&gt; — Mike Novogratz (@novogratz) [May 1, 2024](https://twitter.com/novogratz/status/1785639426875375978?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw)

Ver renounced his U.S. citizenship in 2014 and became a citizen of St. Kitts and Nevis, although he was still obligated to file U.S. tax returns that included earnings from certain assets, such as Bitcoin. 

[Novogratz](https://u.today/mike-novogratzs-galaxy-digital-6000-eth-purchase-signals-institutional-interest) highlights the possibilities in the case, stating that "the feds" often go after cases with more than a 95% chance of winning.  

Expressing hopes that a settlement is reached quickly, Novogratz acknowledges Ver as a pioneer in the space, funding projects that helped create the crypto industry. He further added that while he disagreed with the Bitcoin evangelist's preoccupation with Bitcoin Cash, he always found him to be nice and helpful.   

"Hoping Roger reaches a settlement quickly and moves on with this. He was a pioneer in the space and funded lots of projects that helped create our industry. I really didn’t agree with him on his Bitcoin Cash obsession but always found him kind and helpful," Novogratz wrote.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:39:27 GMT</pubDate><link>https://u.today/billionaire-mike-novogratz-reacts-to-roger-vers-arrest</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Michael Saylor Breaks Silence on Bitcoin's Store-of-Value Qualities

URL Source: https://u.today/michael-saylor-breaks-silence-on-bitcoins-store-of-value-qualities

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:47:00+0000

Markdown Content:
Prominent Bitcoiner Saylor highlights Bitcoin's qualities as opposed to gold, stocks and fiat currencies

![Image 1: Michael Saylor Breaks Silence on Bitcoin's Store-of-Value Qualities](https://u.today/sites/default/files/styles/736x/public/2024-05/s2185.jpg)

Cover image via [www.youtube.com](https://www.youtube.com/watch?si=VhdGeGeyi_MWAzoD&amp;v=h74g3KH_2lo&amp;feature=youtu.be)

Disclaimer: The opinions expressed by our writers are their own and do not represent the views of U.Today. The financial and market information provided on U.Today is intended for informational purposes only. U.Today is not liable for any financial losses incurred while trading cryptocurrencies. Conduct your own research by contacting financial experts before making any investment decisions. We believe that all content is accurate as of the date of publication, but certain offers mentioned may no longer be available.

Founder of MicroStrategy, Bitcoin holding giant, and its chairman, [Michael Saylor,](https://u.today/key-bitcoin-definition-issued-by-michael-saylor-as-btc-stages-decline) continues to endorse the world’s pioneer cryptocurrency in his tweets. This time, in his tweet, he emphasized Bitcoin’s strong qualities as a store of value, comparing it to other assets.

Saylor took to his X/Twitter account to say “Bitcoin is for the money you can't afford to lose.”

On the animated chart that came with the tweet, Saylor showed that since the halving that took place in 2016 (the second halving event in Bitcoin’s history) the percentage of original Bitcoin value relative to Bitcoin has been 100%. Therefore, it has been perfect as a store of value, Michael Saylor hinted, compared to its rivals – gold, the S&amp;P 500, U.S. real estate, the U.S. dollar and three other fiat currencies (albeit used in countries with troublesome economies), the Nigerian naira, the Turkish lira and the Argentine peso.

MicroStrategy adds more Bitcoin in April
----------------------------------------

MicroStrategy, led by Bitcoin evangelist Michael Saylor, announced that during the month of April, it had acquired an additional [BTC lump of 122 coins](https://u.today/heres-how-much-michael-saylors-microstrategy-now-owns-in-bitcoin). That cost the business intelligence giant approximately $7.8 million as it bought those Bitcoins at the price of $63,934.

The company’s Bitcoin stash currently constitutes 214,400 BTC evaluated at a staggering $5.68 billion.

Over the past month, the world’s largest cryptocurrency has seen a massive price reduction as it dropped from above the $72,450 level to the current $58,150 price tag.

Over the past 24 hours, Bitcoin lost roughly 10% after Binance's CZ was sentenced to four months in prison, “Bitcoin Jesus” Roger Ver was arrested for tax evasion in Spain, Hong Kong Bitcoin-Ethereum ETFs failed to meet traders’ expectations on the first trading day and a few other important factors.

About the author

[![Image 2: article image](https://u.today/sites/default/files/2019-11/yuri-ava.jpg)

Yuri Molchan

](https://u.today/yuri-molchan)

Yuri is interested in technology and technical innovations. He has been writing about DLT and crypto since 2017. Believes that blockchain and cryptocurrencies have a potential to transform the world in the future in many of its aspects. He has written for multiple crypto media outlets. His articles have been quoted by such crypto influencers as Tyler Winklevoss, John McAfee, CZ Binance, Max Keiser, etc.

Advertisement

TopCryptoNewsinYourMailbox

TopCryptoNewsinYourMailbox
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:39:55 GMT</pubDate><link>https://u.today/michael-saylor-breaks-silence-on-bitcoins-store-of-value-qualities</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: How Ethereum Founder Vitalik Buterin Keeps His Crypto Safe

URL Source: https://decrypt.co/228946/how-ethereum-founder-vitalik-buterin-keeps-crypto-safe

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:38:51

Markdown Content:
[Ethereum](https://decrypt.co/resources/what-is-ethereum-quickly-explained-four-minute-guide) founder Vitalik Buterin is advising people to "decentralize your own security," after weighing in on a Twitter discussion about using cold wallets.

To prove his point, Buterin said that he keeps 90% of his crypto funds in a mutisig [Safe wallet](https://safe.global/).

"M-of-N, some keys held by you (but not enough to block recovery), the rest held by other people you trust," he wrote. "Don't reveal who those other people are, even to each other."

The "[m-of-n](https://blog.apnic.net/2021/05/28/what-is-m-of-n-in-public-private-key-signing/)" Buterin referred to describes one of the ways multisig, or multi-signature, wallets can be set up. The first variable refers to minimum number of signatures required to sign a contract, therefore spending or transferring funds from the wallet. The second variable refers to the total number of possible signatories that exist for the wallet.

The conversation started after a developer and research, who goes by the pseudonym [0xkofi](https://twitter.com/0xKofi/status/1785294613579730966) on Twitter, urged crypto traders to think about how devastating it would be to lose all their funds and avoid it by investing in cold storage.

&gt; The above is why I use a multisig ([@safe](https://twitter.com/safe?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw)) for &gt;90% of my personal funds 🙂
&gt; 
&gt; M-of-N, some keys held by you (but not enough to block recovery), the rest held by other people you trust. Don't reveal who those other people are, even to each other.
&gt; 
&gt; Decentralize your own security.
&gt; 
&gt; — vitalik.eth (@VitalikButerin) [May 1, 2024](https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1785562273433387320?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw)

"Your hardware wallet will be your fortress of solitude," Kofi wrote. "It will allow you to sleep peacefully at night. It will protect you so that you can survive this game long enough to win."

But not everyone is sold on that being the right way to protect their personal crypto stash. Peter Watts, Uneven Labs CEO and the founder of Reservoir, a developer platform for launching NFT collections, highlighted the risks involved in relying on hardware wallets.

[Vitalik Buterin Pushes for ‘Privacy Pools’ to Balance Anonymity With Regulatory Compliance](https://decrypt.co/155278/vitalik-buterin-pushes-for-privacy-pools-to-balance-anonymity-with-regulatory-compliance)
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin has co-authored a new research paper exploring how a privacy-preserving blockchain protocol could balance the need for user anonymity with regulatory compliance. The paper, co-authored by Buterin along with early Tornado Cash contributor Ameen Soleimani, Jacob Illum from the blockchain security firm Chainalysis, and two researchers from the University of Basel, delves into the subject of establishing a neutral infrastructure to incorporate privacy into blockch...

"When using a hardware wallet, the biggest risk becomes yourself," he wrote, adding that someone might find a stashed private seed phrase, or a user could secure it so well that they can't retrieve it themselves.

That's when Buterin chimed in to describe how he makes sure that he isn't the single point of failure for the security of his cold storage wallet.

Although Safe (formerly Gnosis Safe) multisig wallets have often been treated as a product to help DAOs and other groups manage shared treasuries, there's a lot of individuals who use them in a similar way to Buterin.

"Today, individuals make up more than 99% of Safe users, including notable ones like Vitalik Buterin and [P](https://decrypt.co/144816/nft-artwork-owned-three-arrows-capital-sells-6-2-million-sothebys)unk6529," wrote a SafeDAO contributor and delegate known as [Daniel](https://twitter.com/danftz) on Twitter.

_Edited by [Andrew Hayward](https://decrypt.co/author/andrew-hayward)_

### Stay on top of crypto news, get daily updates in your inbox.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:40:25 GMT</pubDate><link>https://decrypt.co/228946/how-ethereum-founder-vitalik-buterin-keeps-crypto-safe</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Who Holds The Most Ethereum (ETH)? How Coinbase, Grayscale, Robinhood And Binance Stack Up

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554230/who-holds-the-most-ethereum-eth-how-coinbase-grayscale-robinhood-and-binance-stack-up

Published Time: 2024-05-01T10:38:11.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
One of the most interesting aspects of [blockchain](https://www.benzinga.com/money/what-is-blockchain/) is that everything is public. All transactions, wallets and portfolios are entirely accessible to anyone, allowing for an unprecedented amount of insight into a financial asset class. 

The uses of the data can range from monitoring overall trading activity and flows to seeing what the largest wallets and firms are doing with their positions. Arkham Intelligence is a blockchain analytics platform particularly interested in the second application. It cross-references financial disclosures by firms and individuals with on-chain activity to match up entities with specific wallet addresses. 

**Don't Miss:**

*   **Dogecoin millionaires are increasing — [**investors with $1M+ in DOGE revealed!**](https://www.benzinga.com/money/dogecoin-millionaires-adv)**
*   **According to Cathie Wood, holding 6 Ethereum (ETH) could make you a millionaire, [**here’s why it can be true**](https://www.benzinga.com/money/adv-6eth).**

With Arkham's insights, anyone can see how the largest entities in crypto are trading. One interesting application is looking at the largest firms in the space.

Coinbase, one of the largest crypto companies in the world, operates a centralized exchange, wallet service and a layer-2 called Base. [Coinbase's portfolio](https://platform.arkhamintelligence.com/explorer/entity/coinbase) is worth nearly $80 billion. The wallet is composed almost entirely of Ethereum (ETH) and Bitcoin (BTC). The firm holds over 900,000 BTC, currently worth over $55 billion. It also holds over 6.6 million ETH worth roughly $20 billion. 

While Coinbase operates as a crypto custodian, Grayscale is a crypto asset manager. It creates a handful of funds and ETFs that allow investors to access crypto products. In January, it was one of the first companies to offer a [spot Bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF)](https://www.benzinga.com/money/best-spot-bitcoin-etfs) converted from a previously released futures ETF. Grayscale's portfolio has more than 99% of its value in ETH and BTC. It owns 303,050 BTC worth $18.6 billion and 2.98 million ETH worth $9 billion. Grayscale holds $27.6 billion in crypto assets. 

**Trending: 1 in 4 Americans own a share of Bitcoin according to NASDAQ, [**how much would $10 get you today**](https://www.benzinga.com/money/kraken)?**

While it is mostly known for its equity platform, Robinhood began offering crypto several years ago. The crypto platform offers a handful of the most popular tokens, but the portfolio is mostly invested in ETH, BTC and Shiba Inu (SHIB). The wallet has 140,000 BTC worth $8.6 billion, 1.5 million ETH worth $4.7 billion and 42.5 trillion SHIB worth $1 billion. 

As the largest crypto exchange in the world, it is no surprise that Binance (BNB) has the largest portfolio, worth over $200 billion. It holds 165 million BNB worth $94 billion, 640,000 BTC worth $40 billion, $27.2 billion worth of Tether (USDT) and 4.4 million ETH worth $13.2 billion. 

Coinbase has the largest ETH holding on the list. Its $20 billion of ETH is more than 5% of the total supply. The four firms hold a combined 15.5 million ETH, which is roughly 12.7% of the supply. 

While this may make it seem like the supply of ETH is heavily concentrated among a few entities, Coinbase, Robinhood and Binance hold assets for their customers. The portion of the supply held by these firms is under the discretion of the millions of people who hold ETH on these brokerages. 

**Read Next:**

*   **Bitcoin has jumped another 45% already this year – [**how much would you need to get started today?**](https://www.benzinga.com/money/kraken)**
*   **If you invested $100 in DOGE when Elon Musk first tweeted about it in 2019, [**here’s how much you’d have today**](https://www.benzinga.com/money/etoro-doge).**

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:40:47 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554230/who-holds-the-most-ethereum-eth-how-coinbase-grayscale-robinhood-and-binance-stack-up?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Bitcoin Could </description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:41:39 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.coindesk.com/business/2024/05/01/bitcoin-could-drop-further-to-as-low-as-50k-standard-chartered-says/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Dutch exchange Bitvavo taps Figment to expand staking services

URL Source: https://cointelegraph.com/news/figment-staking-dutch-exchange-bitvavo

Published Time: 2024-05-01T14:34:20.000Z

Markdown Content:
Institutional staking platform Figment will become an additional infrastructure provider to Dutch exchange Bitvavo.

![Image 1: Dutch exchange Bitvavo taps Figment to expand staking services](https://images.cointelegraph.com/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=90,width=1434/https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/ea096730-eff6-49aa-88fd-412bc0a7cf88.jpg)

Own this piece of crypto history

[Collect this article as NFT](https://mint.cointelegraph.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcointelegraph.com%2Fnews%2Ffigment-staking-dutch-exchange-bitvavo&amp;utm_source=cointelegraph_com&amp;utm_medium=button&amp;utm_campaign=articles)

Update (May. 1 at 15h00 UTC): This article has been updated to include additional information about Figment's partnership with Bitvavo.

Netherlands cryptocurrency exchange Bitvavo will tap into staking platform Figment’s institutional-grade infrastructure to stake a variety of tokens on behalf of its users.

Figment, which attracted significant investments from the likes of [Galaxy Digital in 2021](https://cointelegraph.com/news/galaxy-digital-backs-50m-funding-round-for-crypto-staking-outfit-figment), [announced](https://figment.io/insights/bitvavos-digital-asset-staking-now-powered-by-figment/?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=share&amp;utm_term=5-1&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=content) that it would provide staking infrastructure for the Dutch exchange. Bitvavo will stake user assets across multiple proof-of-stake protocols including Ethereum, Solana and NEAR.

A statement from Bitvavo CEO and co-founder Mark Nuvelstijn highlighted the exchange’s efforts to review and enhance its product and services. The company also confirmed that Figment is an expansion and diversification of its pool staking service providers that includes Coinbase, Copper and Kiln.

Nuvelstijn added that staking has become an integral part of the cryptocurrency industry and that the provision is an essential service for its customer base of more than 1.5 million users across the Benelux region.

The Bitvavo CEO said that working with Figment would allow the exchange to provide additional security and safety around staking and expand the offering:

&gt; “Figment is one of the staking infrastructure leaders in the market, and we continue to be impressed by their staking- and up-to-date market knowledge.”

Figment EMEA head Eva Lawrence said the two teams have been working together for six months with the view of spearheading the exchange’s staking services across Europe.

The partnership is set to provide access to staking rewards on Bitvavo on newly launched networks. Figment is also establishing dedicated validator nodes for Bitvavo to provide high-quality network performance and security.

The Dutch exchange has continued a steady approach to expanding its footprint into Europe. [In Nov. 2023](https://cointelegraph.com/news/dutch-exchange-bitvavo-cleared-to-operate-in-france), it announced the launch of services to French users after successfully registering as a digital asset service provider with France’s Autorité des Marchés Financiers (AMF).

The expansion into France followed Bitvavo's regulatory approval to offer its services in Austria. The exchange expanded its offering to Italy in 2022 and has filed registration applications for other major European markets.

Nuvelstijn previously [spoke exclusively](https://cointelegraph.com/news/no-concerns-over-bitcoin-halving-supply-shock-says-bitvavo-ceo) to Cointelegraph during the European Blockchain Convention held in Barcelona in Oct. 2023, highlighting his belief that Europe's Markets in Crypto Assets (MiCA) framework will allow cryptocurrency companies to offer financials services and vice versa

**_Magazine: [68% of Runes are in the red — Are they really an upgrade for Bitcoin?](https://cointelegraph.com/magazine/runes-supporters-unlock-bitcoins-potential/)_**

Explore more articles like this

Subscribe to the Markets Outlook newsletter

![Image 2: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](https://images.cointelegraph.com/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=90,width=96/https://s3.cointelegraph.com/storage/uploads/view/3c6021603a7455fadda1e3a4f4ee1e7a.svg)

Get critical insights to spot investment opportunities, mitigate risks, and refine your trading strategies. Delivered every Monday

![Image 3](https://zoa.cointelegraph.com/pixel?postId=129089&amp;regionId=1)
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:42:07 GMT</pubDate><link>https://cointelegraph.com/news/figment-staking-dutch-exchange-bitvavo</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Spot Bitcoin ETFs Bled Another $162 Million On Tuesday - Grayscale Bitcoin Trust (BTC) Common Units of fr

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554103/spot-bitcoin-etfs-bled-another-162-million-on-tuesday

Published Time: 2024-05-01T10:33:17.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
[Bitcoin spot Exchange-Traded Funds](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/04/38518143/hong-kongs-bitcoin-etf-debut-records-0-2-of-first-day-us-etf-trading-volume) (ETFs) experienced a substantial outflow of funds, totaling $162 million on Tuesday, according to financial analytics firm SoSoValue.

**What Happened**: The **Grayscale Bitcoin Trust** GBTC alone saw a [withdrawal](https://sosovalue.xyz/assets/etf) of $93.2277 million, contributing significantly to its historical net outflow of $17.303 billion. **Fidelity’s** FBTC FBTC bled $35.28 million, while **Bitwise’s** BITB BITB saw an outflow of $34.31 million. **Ark’s ETF ARKB** ARKB was the only ETF recording a net inflow, albeit a modest $3.6 million.

Following these developments, the total net asset value of **Bitcoin** BTC/USD spot ETFs fell below the $50 billion mark, landing at $49.413 billion.

[![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)](https://www.benzinga.com/events/digital-assets/)

_Also Read: [Patrick McHenry Questions SEC’s Transparency On Ethereum As A Security](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38548916/patrick-mchenry-questions-secs-transparency-on-ethereum-as-a-security)_

**Why It Matters**: This trend of outflows contrasts sharply with the optimism surrounding the launch of new cryptocurrency spot ETFs in Hong Kong.

Harvest Global Investments and other firms received approval from the Hong Kong Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) to offer Bitcoin and Ethereum spot ETFs, which started trading on April 30, [according](https://wublock.substack.com/p/hong-kong-cryptocurrency-etf-first?r=jbpop&amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;triedRedirect=true) to Wu Blockchain.

Notably, the initial offering of these ETFs saw significant interest from regions including Singapore and the Middle East, though Chinese mainland investors remain excluded from participating due to regulatory restrictions.

ChinaAMC led the launch with its Bitcoin and Ethereum spot ETFs, boasting an initial offering size that surpassed $125 million—optimistically compared to U.S. launches by industry insiders.

However, the actual first-day trading volume in Hong Kong reached only $12 million, dwarfed by the $4.6 billion volume observed in the U.S. market on similar opening days.

This discrepancy underscores the varying investor appetite and market dynamics between the regions.

Despite the tepid trading volume, Hong Kong’s market showed signs of growth, with the listing of these ETFs heralded as a significant development in the region's financial landscape.

The SFC has outlined a comprehensive regulatory framework for these products, emphasizing the potential risks associated with high volatility and speculation in cryptocurrencies.

**What’s Next**: Looking ahead, the [Future of Digital Assets](https://www.benzinga.com/events/digital-assets/agenda/) event, scheduled by Benzinga on Nov. 19, is set to delve deeper into these developments.

_Read Next: [Ex-Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao Sees Crypto Industry Entering ‘New Phase’](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38547115/ex-binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao-sees-crypto-industry-entering-new-phase)_

_Image: Shutterstock_

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:42:30 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554103/spot-bitcoin-etfs-bled-another-162-million-on-tuesday?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: RWA Tokenizati</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:43:21 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.coindesk.com/business/2024/05/01/rwa-tokenization-firm-securitize-raises-47m-led-by-fund-partner-blackrock/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Bitcoin Price Prediction 2024-2030: A Good Investment? | Cryptopolitan

URL Source: https://www.cryptopolitan.com/bitcoin-price-prediction-2024-2030/

Markdown Content:
### BTC Price Predictions 2024-2033

*   [B](#Bitcoin-(BTC)-Price-Prediction-2023)[itcoin Price Prediction 2024 – up to **$1,10,203**](#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2024)
*   [Bitcoin Price Prediction 2027 – up to **$3,43,302**](#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2027)
*   [Bitcoin Price Prediction 20](#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2029)[30](#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2030) [– up to **$11,22,987**](#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2029)
*   [Bitcoin Price Prediction 2033- up to **$31,09,892**](#Bitcoin-Price-Prediction-2033)

### How much is Bitcoin (BTC) worth?

Today, the price of Bitcoin stands at $63,930, with a trading volume over the past 24 hours reaching $24 billion. Its market capitalization is $1.3 trillion, and it currently commands 54% of the market share. Over the last 24 hours, the BTC price has experienced a 1.5% increase. As for its circulating supply, 19.46 million BTC are in circulation out of a maximum possible supply of 21 million BTC.

Bitcoin price analysis: BTC price declined heavily as it dropped toward $62K
----------------------------------------------------------------------------

**TL; DR Breakdown**

*   BTC price analysis shows that Bitcoin faced a bearish pattern as the price dropped below $63K
*   Resistance for BTC is present at $65,260
*   Support for BTC/USD is present at $62,464

The BTC price analysis for 28 April confirms that bears sparked a solid selling pressure as BTC price plunged buying confidence by heading below the $63K mark. However, BTC price is facing a minor upward correction now.

### BTC price analysis 1-day chart: Bitcoin price faces intense bearish pressure

Analyzing the daily price chart of Bitcoin, BTC’s price faced a robust selling pressure as the price continued to decline below immediate Fib channels and headed toward the $62K level. However, the price is facing a surge in buying demand from the recent low. The 24-hour volume has surged to $252 million, showing an increased interest in trading activity today. BTC price is currently trading at $63,930, increasing by over 1.5% in the last 24 hours.

![Image 1: btc - btc - btc - btc - btc -](https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-28_11-30-55-1200x524.png)

The RSI-14 trend line has declined from its previous level and currently trades below the midline at level 45, hinting that a bearish pressure is on the edge. The SMA-14 level suggests volatility in the next few hours.   

### BTC/USD 4-hour price chart: Bulls aim for an immediate correction above moving averages

The 4-hour Bitcoin price chart suggests that bears are strengthening their position as they are aiming to send the price below the Fib lines. However, bulls are maintaining buying confidence and are aiming to hold the price above the EMA20 trend line.

![Image 2: a chart showing the price of btc](https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-28_11-37-00-1200x524.jpg)

The BoP indicator is trading in a negative region at 0.19, showing that short-term sellers are taking a chance to accelerate a downward trend.

Additionally, the MACD trend line has formed bearish candles below the signal line and the indicator aims for a negative momentum, strengthening short-position holders’ confidence.

### What to expect from BTC price analysis next?

The hourly price chart confirms that Bitcoin attempts to drop below the immediate support line; however, bulls are eyeing for further recovery rally in the upcoming hours. If BTC’s price successfully holds its momentum above $65,260, it will fuel a bullish rally to $67,186.

![Image 3: btc - btc - btc - btc - btc -](https://www.cryptopolitan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BTCUSD_2024-04-28_11-27-27-1-1200x524.png)

If bulls fail to initiate a surge, BTC price may drop below the immediate support line at $62,464, which may begin a bearish trend to $59,942.

Bitcoin has historically presented the opportunity for significant returns due to its decentralized nature. Bitcoin also holds the potential to act as an asset that does not correlate with the broader market trends, akin to gold. This characteristic suggests that it could move independently of other assets such as stocks. Additionally, the recent launch of spot Bitcoin ETFs has made it a good investment option with bright market potential.

Recent BTC News/Opinions
------------------------

**Blackrock’s IBIT**: Blackrock has a Bitcoin fund called the Ishares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT). This fund, which deals with Bitcoin directly, has increased its Bitcoin holdings to more than 252,011 BTC. This means the fund’s Bitcoin is worth about $18 billion now. There’s a big increase in interest from small investors, more than what Blackrock’s boss thought would happen.

**Morgan Stanley In Bitcoin ETF**: Morgan Stanley is planning to add Bitcoin funds to its brokerage platform. This comes after the SEC approved spot Bitcoin ETF in January.

**SEC Approves Spot Bitcoin ETF:** The U.S. has approved spot Bitcoin ETF. The Securities and Exchange Commission announced this decision on 11 January.

Bitcoin Price Predictions 2024-2033
-----------------------------------

### Price Predictions By Cryptopolitan

![Image 4: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==)

&lt;table&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Minimum ($)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Average ($)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Maximum ($)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2024&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;93,269.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;96,768.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,10,203.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,35,384.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,39,255.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,58,198.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2026&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,95,360.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2,02,323.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2,39,224.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2027&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2,92,569.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;3,02,686.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;3,43,302.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2028&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4,36,287.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4,48,394.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;5,08,574.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2029&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;6,33,596.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;6,51,532.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;7,60,170.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2030&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;8,93,504.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;9,19,565.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;11,22,987.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2031&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;12,90,182.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;13,36,160.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;15,24,028.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2032&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;18,50,345.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;19,03,792.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;22,29,599.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2033&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;26,17,633.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;27,12,822.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;31,09,892.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

#### Bitcoin Price Prediction 2024

The BTC price is expected to hit a minimum of $93,269 in 2024, with the potential to reach up to $110,203. The average price forecast stands at $96,768.

#### Bitcoin Price Prediction 2025

The forecast for 2025 suggests Bitcoin could reach a low of $135,384 and may climb to a high of $158,198, with an average price of $139,255.

#### BTC Price Forecast for 2026

Bitcoin’s value in 2026 is anticipated to fall not lower than $195,360, with a ceiling of $239,224. The expected average price is $202,323.

#### Bitcoin (BTC) Price Prediction 2027

In 2027, Bitcoin is forecasted to have a minimum price of $292,569 and may reach a maximum of $343,302, averaging at $302,686.

#### Bitcoin Price Prediction 2028

Predictions for 2028 indicate a minimum Bitcoin price of $436,287, with the potential for a high of $508,574. The average price is expected to be $448,394.

#### Bitcoin Price Prediction 2029

The minimum price for Bitcoin in 2029 is forecasted at $633,596, with a maximum potential of $760,170. The average price is anticipated to be $651,532.

#### Bitcoin (BTC) Price Prediction 2030

For 2030, Bitcoin is expected to reach a minimum of $893,504 and could rise to $1,122,987, with an average trading price of $919,565.

#### Bitcoin Price Forecast 2031

By 2031, Bitcoin’s price could hit a minimum of $1,290,182 and a maximum of $1,524,028, with the average price projected at $1,336,160.

#### Bitcoin (BTC) Price Prediction 2032

The forecast for 2032 suggests a minimum price of $1,850,345 for Bitcoin, with a potential high of $2,229,599. The average price is expected to be $1,903,792.

#### Bitcoin Price Prediction 2033

In 2033, Bitcoin’s price is predicted to be at least $2,617,633, with the possibility of reaching $3,109,892. The average trading value is forecasted at $2,712,822.

### Bitcoin Price Prediction By Coincodex

According to the current Bitcoin price prediction by Coincodex, it is forecasted that the price of Bitcoin will increase by 27.37% to reach $89,852 by May 1, 2024. Technical indicators suggest a bullish sentiment, while the Fear &amp; Greed Index indicates extreme greed at a level of 79.

Over the past 30 days, Bitcoin has seen 17 out of 30 days (57%) in the green, with a price volatility of 4.18%. Coincodex’s forecast suggests that it is currently a favorable time to purchase Bitcoin. Reflecting on historical price trends and BTC halving cycles, Coincodex estimates the yearly low for Bitcoin in 2025 to be around $71,247, with a potential high reaching up to $160,024 the following year.

### Bitcoin Price Prediction By Digital Coin Price

According to Digital Coin Price, there is a forecast suggesting that Bitcoin could surpass the $181,098.63 mark and sustain its market position by the end of 2025. It is estimated that the lowest Bitcoin price may range between $151,521.25 and $181,098.63, with the most probable price stabilizing at approximately $165,414.37 by the close of 2025. Despite the significant fluctuations in its value and the debates over its environmental impact due to energy consumption, billionaire venture capitalist Tim Draper maintains his forecast that Bitcoin will hit $181,098.63 by the end of 2025 or early in the year.

Further predictions by Digital Coin Price indicate that by 2032, Bitcoin’s price could minimally reach $968,037.25, with an average trading price throughout the year of $999,217.60, potentially peaking at $1,013,559.06. Experts from Digital Coin Price anticipate the maximum trading price to hover around $999,217.60.

### Bitcoin Price Prediction By CryptoPredictions.com

Cryptopredictions.com forecasts that Bitcoin will begin May 2024 at a value of $51,587.956 and conclude the month at $51,833.923. Throughout May, the maximum projected BTC price is anticipated to reach $68,302.039, while the minimum price could drop to $46,445.386.

BTC Price Overview
------------------

The price of Bitcoin had experienced notable peaks and troughs in its value. Despite this volatility, the unique nature of the Bitcoin network and its limited supply of coins has attracted the attention of investors and traders worldwide. The [blockchain](https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/blockchain/) technology underlying Bitcoin enables secure and transparent transactions without the need for intermediaries, making it an attractive alternative to traditional financial systems.

In recent years, Bitcoin has trended upwards, with significant increases in value occurring in 2017 and 2021. This growth has been driven by a variety of factors, including increased adoption and acceptance of Bitcoin as a form of payment, as well as speculation by investors and traders. Today, Bitcoin is trading at +56654654.6% above its all-time low in July 2010.

While the future of Bitcoin’s price remains uncertain, many experts predict that the trend towards increased adoption and acceptance of digital currencies will continue to drive demand for Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies.

BTC Price history
-----------------

Bitcoin’s (BTC) price again reached an all-time high in 2021, as values exceeded over 65,000 USD in November 2021. That particular price hike was connected to the launch of a Bitcoin ETF in the United States, whilst others in 2021 were due to events involving Tesla and Coinbase, respectively.

Tesla’s announcement in March 2021 that it had acquired 1.5 billion U.S. dollars worth of the digital coin fueled mass interest.  The market was noticeably different by the end of 2022, however, with Bitcoin prices reaching roughly $17194.91 as of January 10, 2023, after another crypto exchange, FTX, filed for bankruptcy.

Large BTC holders – ‘whales’ – are said to make up two percent of anonymous ownership accounts, and own approx 92 percent of BTC. As most people who use cryptocurrency-related services worldwide are retail clients rather than institutional investors, Bitcoin prices are difficult to measure, as movements from one large whale already have a significant impact on this market.

More on Bitcoin
---------------

### What is Bitcoin?

Launched in 2009, Bitcoin is a decentralized digital currency powered by blockchain technology. Satoshi Nakamoto created the coin to overcome the shortcomings of government-issued currencies without requiring a controlling authority.

Bitcoin (BTC) was created out of the need for a cryptography-based e-payment system rather than the conventional trust-based system. Cryptocurrency acts as a store of value and a payment method for any transaction process in the crypto space. It is often dubbed “digital gold.”

Bitcoin’s current cryptography is based on an impenetrable algorithm (SHA-256) designed by the United States National Security Agency (NSA) in 2016, after the collapse of the SHA-1 algorithm. This algorithm makes it impossible to crack the Bitcoin network.

Since the launch of Bitcoin in 2009, its value has risen dramatically, from less than 0.01 USD in May 2010 to over 67,000 USD in November 2021. Bitcoin is expected to attain newer feats in the coming years as more institutional investors and traders continue to turn to cryptocurrency.

### What Influences Bitcoin’s Price?

The world’s premier cryptocurrency, Bitcoin, has recently taken a substantial hit, dipping below the $25.5K threshold and reaching its lowest value in three months. This downward trend follows a lawsuit initiated by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) against [Binance](https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/binance-bnb/), a leading cryptocurrency exchange, and its founder and CEO, Changpeng Zhao (CZ).

The news of this legal dispute sparked a swift wave of Bitcoin selling, causing a [ripple](https://www.cryptopolitan.com/news/ripple-xrp/) effect across the majority of other cryptocurrencies. The market strain has escalated as the SEC has expanded its legal pursuits to encompass Coinbase, another key contender in the cryptocurrency exchange market.

Crypto experts posit that if Bitcoin can hold its resistance level at $26,000, we might see a bounce back in the coming months. However, if this level is breached, Bitcoin could potentially tumble to its lowest ever value of $20,000.

Yet, the experts also caution that the current rise in interest rates and a more stringent monetary policy might hinder Bitcoin from making a significant recovery in the near term.

Despite these hurdles, the year 2023 holds promise for Bitcoin advocates who see it as a “digital safe-haven” or “virtual gold”. These enthusiasts are confident that Bitcoin can offer investors a substantial hedge or attractive yields during periods of market instability.

### Bitcoin Challenges

Despite its success, Bitcoin has faced several criticisms, especially its energy-hungry mining system. According to an energy consumption tracker developed by the University of Cambridge, Bitcoin mining was estimated to consume 100 TWh per year, about one-third of the UK’s total energy consumption in 2016.

In addition, BTC’s criminality potential has positioned it for more scrutiny, as it has facilitated numerous dark web dealings, such as acquiring illegal weapons, money laundering, etc.

The most significant and long-standing challenge of Bitcoin is scalability. Bitcoin’s underlying technology limits its performance in terms of transaction completion timeframe, with an insufficient capacity of 3-7 TPS. As more transactions are initiated on the network, processing delays will surface. Several proposals have been put forward to nip this concern in the bud, but a favorable long-term fix remains unclear.

### How do you buy and sell Bitcoin?

You can buy and [sell Bitcoin](https://www.cryptopolitan.com/how-to-sell-bitcoin-everything-you-need/) through cryptocurrency exchanges or peer-to-peer platforms. To purchase Bitcoin, you typically need to create an account with a cryptocurrency exchange, fund your account, and place an order to buy Bitcoin.

### What is Bitcoin’s role in the broader financial system?

Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies are seen by some as a disruptive force that could challenge traditional financial systems and provide greater financial freedom and autonomy for users.

### Where to store Bitcoin?

The best ways to store Bitcoin include hardware wallets, paper wallets, and software wallets. Hardware wallets are considered the most secure, as they store private keys offline and require physical confirmation of transactions. Paper wallets, which involve printing out private keys and keeping them in a secure location, are also considered secure but require careful handling. Software wallets, which run on computers or mobile devices, are a great option, but more vulnerable to hacking and malware attacks.

### What drives the value of BTC?

Bitcoin’s value is determined by supply and demand factors, such as market sentiment, adoption rates, regulatory changes, and investor speculation. Bitcoin’s decentralized nature, scarcity, and high-security features also contribute to its value in the market.

Conclusion
----------

Bitcoin has gained the mainstream adoption following massive interest from institutional giants. Some companies, like the Spanish firm Telefonica, now accept Bitcoin. Telefonica even works with a cryptocurrency exchange called Bit2Me to let people pay with Bitcoin.

Looking ahead, Bitcoin seems to have a bright future with potential for its price to go up. This prediction is based on Bitcoin’s past prices and current market sentiment. Adding Bitcoin to your investment portfolio could be a good move, but it’s important to do your research and understand the risks before buying Bitcoin or any other cryptocurrency
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:43:47 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/bitcoin-price-prediction-2024-2030/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Meme Coin Bloodbath: Base, Solana Meme Cryptos Decimated

URL Source: https://u.today/meme-coin-bloodbath-base-solana-meme-cryptos-decimated

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:15:00+0000

Markdown Content:
Contents

*   [Base meme coins segment loses 24% in 24 hours](#h260)
*   [Crypto liquidations near $400 million](#h348)

Shiba Inu (SHIB) and Dogecoin (DOGE) competitors on Solana (SOL) and Base (BASE) blockchains are under pressure as Bitcoin (BTC) dropped below $60,000. In the last seven days, the Base meme crypto scene lost over one-third of its value.

Base meme coins segment loses 24% in 24 hours
---------------------------------------------

The segments of Base (BASE) and Solana (SOL) meme cryptocurrencies are yet again among the most affected categories of altcoins hit by a massive crypto price flush. In the last 24 hours, meme coins on Base (BASE) saw almost 24% of their capitalization erased.

![Image 1: Base meme coins under biggest pressure](https://u.today/sites/default/files/inline-images/47837_1.png)

_Image by_ [_CoinGecko_](https://www.coingecko.com/en/categories)

Among all Base (BASE) meme coins, the biggest losses are registered by low-cap assets. However, flagship coins of the Base (BASE) meme crypto ecosystem - BRETT, DEGEN, HIGHER - also witnessed 10%-15% drops. 

Cat-themed meme coins represent the fifth worst affected category on CoinGecko, with 17% lost overnight. However, its leaders - Cat In The Dog World (MEW) and Mog Coin (MOG) - printed tiny 3-4% losses and, therefore, even outperformed the crypto market as a whole.

The Solana (SOL) meme coin ecosystem lost 15% in 24 hours with leaders WIF, BONK and BOME only erasing 1-6% of their prices.

As covered by U.Today previously, meme coins on Solana (SOL) and Base (BASE) were also hit by last weekend's price plunge.

Crypto liquidations near $400 million
-------------------------------------

In the last 24 hours, total capitalization of cryptocurrency markets plummeted by 3.9%. Bitcoin (BTC), the flagship cryptocurrency, lost 5.7% of its value.

This flush can be attributed to the end of Binance's CZ trial and the paltry start of Hong Kong crypto-based spot ETFs.

As a result, numerous Bitcoin (BTC) and altcoin futures traders were liquidated in the last 24 hours. Over $390 million in positions, mostly longs, were erased, CoinGlass's data [shows](https://www.coinglass.com/LiquidationData).

Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH) are responsible for $250 million of this sum.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:44:12 GMT</pubDate><link>https://u.today/meme-coin-bloodbath-base-solana-meme-cryptos-decimated</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Elliptic Uncovers New Bitcoin Money Laundering Pattern After Training ML Model Using 200 Million Transactions

URL Source: https://dailycoin.com/elliptic-uncovers-novel-bitcoin-money-laundering-pattern/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:08:22+00:00

Markdown Content:
Elliptic highlights a novel Bitcoin money laundering pattern employed by illicit actors.

*   [![Image 1: Brian Danga](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Brian-Danga-50x50.png)](https://dailycoin.com/author/brian-danga/"BrianDanga")


by Fact checked by: [Ciaran Lawler](https://dailycoin.com/author/ciaran-lawler/"Factcheckedby:CiaranLawler"), Editor: [Stefan Trapp](https://dailycoin.com/author/stefan-trapp/"Editor:StefanTrapp")

Published: May 1, 2024 │ 3:08 PM GMT

![Image 2: Bitcoin faced character manipulating network.](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin_btc_etf_network_defi_power_connect_fix_unbranded_web.jpg)

_Created by Kornelija Poderskytė from DailyCoin_

[![Image 3: Google News Follow Button](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/themes/cryptotimes/assets/img/follow-google-news-dailycoin-cryptonews.png)](https://news.google.com/publications/CAAqBwgKMIjkmAswmO6wAw?ceid=IN:en&amp;oc=3)

*   **Elliptic has published new research on Bitcoin money laundering.**
*   **The latest study continues previous research published by the firm in 2019.**
*   **The firm uncovered an emerging trend in BTC money laundering.**

[Blockchain](https://dailycoin.com/tag/blockchain/) forensics firm Elliptic said Wednesday it has made significant progress in using artificial intelligence (AI) to identify [Bitcoin](https://dailycoin.com/bitcoin-btc-birth-cryptocurrency-blockchain-revolution/) transactions made by illicit actors.

Elliptic published its first research in 2019 after training a machine learning model using over 200,00 transactions. In the second research, published on May 1, the firm trained the model using a vast dataset containing nearly 200 million transactions.

**New Bitcoin Money Laundering Pattern**
----------------------------------------

In a [blogpost](https://www.elliptic.co/blog/our-new-research-enhancing-blockchain-analytics-through-ai) spotlighting the new research, Elliptic said it had detected potential money laundering instances on the Bitcoin network after training the machine learning model to identify “subgraphs,” chain of transactions representing BTC being laundered.

“By identifying these subgraphs rather than illicit wallets, this approach allows us to focus on the “multi-hop laundering process more generally rather than the on-chain behavior of specific illicit actors,” Elliptic said.

Of 52 “money laundering” subgraphs predicted by the model and which ended up with deposits to an exchange involved in the research, 14 were confirmed to have been received by users who had already been flagged as being linked to possible money laundering.

The research further uncovered new types of emerging money laundering patterns on the Bitcoin network, such as the use of “intermediary nested” in certain ways.

Intermediary nested services include businesses that move funds through accounts at larger exchanges, often without the exchange’s awareness in the case of illicit activity.

“Nested services are known to frequently have less stringent customer due diligence checks than the cryptocurrency exchanges they utilize, or sometimes have no such anti-money laundering checks at all, resulting in their misuse for cryptocurrency laundering.” Elliptic described.

The latest research was co-authored by Elliptic and MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab researchers.

This article is for information purposes only and should not be considered trading or investment advice. Nothing herein shall be construed as financial, legal, or tax advice. Trading forex, cryptocurrencies, and CFDs pose a considerable risk of loss.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:44:44 GMT</pubDate><link>https://dailycoin.com/elliptic-uncovers-novel-bitcoin-money-laundering-pattern/?utm_source=cryptopanic&amp;utm_medium=rss</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Capitulation incoming? Bitcoin miners' revenue drops to a 6-month low

URL Source: https://finbold.com/capitulation-incoming-bitcoin-miners-revenue-drops-to-a-6-month-low/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:13:01+00:00

Markdown Content:
Bitcoin’s ([BTC](https://finbold.com/cryptocurrency/bitcoin/)) price shambled post-halving, with consecutive losses and the first [“red month” in April, after a 7-month green streak](https://finbold.com/bitcoin-price-red-alert-as-7-month-green-streak-ends-how-bad-is-it/). In this context, the Bitcoin miners’ revenue in USD dropped to a 6-month low, slightly above $30 million.

Finbold retrieved [data](https://www.blockchain.com/explorer/charts/miners-revenue) from _Blockchain.com_ on May 1, showing $30.17 million of miners’ revenue collected on April 30. Moreover, the 1-year chart illustrates this as the lowest revenue for Bitcoin miners in the past six months.

Notably, the most significant drop occurred after Bitcoin’s fourth halving, when the block subsidy reward changed from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC per mined block, drastically affecting the activity’s profitability.

### Picks for you

However, the situation worsened as the Bitcoin price in USD moved from around $70,000 to $57,000 month-over-month.

![Image 1: a graph showing the miners revenue](https://assets.finbold.com/uploads/2024/05/Bitcoin-miners-revenue-1024x576.jpg)

Bitcoin Miners Revenue, 1-year chart. Source: _Blockchain.com_

Bitcoin miners underwater, mining with losses as revenue drops
--------------------------------------------------------------

As reported by Finbold on April 23, [Bitcoin miners are “underwater” with increased production costs](https://finbold.com/bitcoin-miners-underwater-as-production-costs-surge-post-halving/), mining BTC with losses. At that time, data from different sources estimated losses from $36,000 to $52,000 per [Bitcoin mined](https://finbold.com/guide/bitcoin-mining-guide/), with BTC trading at $66,000.

Again, this situation worsened amid the most recent [cryptocurrency market](https://finbold.com/category/cryptocurrency-news/) crash, which [liquidated long-position traders by $400 million](https://finbold.com/long-position-traders-lost-400-million-in-a-24-hour-bloodbath/). According to the previous sources, Bitcoin miners could be losing between $43,000 and $72,000 per BTC in this revenue drop.

In particular, _Capriole Investments_ has the most pessimistic production cost estimation of $128,989 per mined Bitcoin. The investment firm estimates that $77,400 is spent on electrical costs for each produced coin, considering [hashrate](https://finbold.com/guide/hashrate/#) averages.

![Image 2: a graph showing the production cost of bitcoin](https://assets.finbold.com/uploads/2024/05/Bitcoin-electrical-cost-capriole-1024x728.jpg)

Bitcoin Production Cost and Electrical Cost. Source: _Capriole Investments_

Meanwhile, [data](https://en.macromicro.me/charts/29435/bitcoin-production-total-cost) from _MacroMicro_ shows a less-worse cost/price ratio of 1.66, according to estimates from _Cambridge University_. As per this data, Bitcoin’s average mining cost was above $100,500 on April 30, close to historical highs in production costs, with miners theoretically losing around $43,000 for each BTC they issue.

![Image 3: a graph showing the price of bitcoin and ethereum](https://assets.finbold.com/uploads/2024/05/Bitcoin-average-mining-cost-macromicro-1-1024x343.jpg)

Bitcoin Average Mining Costs. Source: _MacroMicro_

Therefore, current data suggests potential industry turmoil that could cause some Bitcoin mining companies to capitulate. To prevent that, the Bitcoin price would need to rally above the estimated production costs, now at all-time highs.

If the production costs remain higher than the mining rewards, measured in U.S. dollars, the Bitcoin network could centralize in a few big miners. Experts have [warned](https://twitter.com/ColinLeMahieu/status/1778052049319412079) about that for years, mentioning the Economy of Scale dynamics inherent to Bitcoin, which threatens the system’s security.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:45:37 GMT</pubDate><link>https://finbold.com/capitulation-incoming-bitcoin-miners-revenue-drops-to-a-6-month-low/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Defiant CZ Accepts Prison Sentence, Vows 'I Will Do My Time' and Move Forward

URL Source: https://dailycoin.com/cz-vows-to-focus-on-next-chapter-after-sentencing/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:00:00+00:00

Markdown Content:
CZ Vows to Focus on ‘Next Chapter’ After Sentencing
---------------------------------------------------

CZ escapes with a light sentence in money laundering case, vows to embrace new path after prison stint.

*   [![Image 1: Samuel Wan](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/Samuel-3-50x50.png)](https://dailycoin.com/author/samuel-wan/"SamuelWan")


Published: May 1, 2024 │ 3:00 PM GMT

![Image 2: Binance CZ is on a danger path.](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/binance_cz_burning_empire_Changpeng-Zhao_web.jpg)

_Created by Kornelija Poderskytė from DailyCoin_

[![Image 3: Google News Follow Button](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/themes/cryptotimes/assets/img/follow-google-news-dailycoin-cryptonews.png)](https://news.google.com/publications/CAAqBwgKMIjkmAswmO6wAw?ceid=IN:en&amp;oc=3)

*   **After six months of waiting, a** **judge** **sentence****d** **CZ** **to** **imprisonment** **on April 30.**
*   **CZ** **expressed** **regret** **over his** **failures** **in running** **Binance****.** 
*   **The former** **Binance** **CEO** **intends to serve the** **sentence** **but looks forward to future** **projects****.** 

After a multi-year investigation, US authorities charged Binance and its co-founder Changpeng Zhao (CZ) with violating money laundering rules in November 2023. As part of the settlement, the company agreed to pay a $4.3 billion fine and exit the US market. The deal also involved CZ stepping down as company CEO, paying a $50 million fine, and pleading guilty to money laundering.

After months of legal limbo, Judge Richard Jones finally gave sentencing on April 30, ordering that CZ serve a four-month prison sentence. CZ responded by saying, “I will do my time,” and move forward after the ordeal is over. 

Looking to the Future
---------------------

Responding to the sentencing, CZ put on a brave face, stating that he intends to serve his sentence and put the matter behind him once it is done. Looking to the future, CZ stated that he will remain a passive crypto investor and plans to “focus on the next chapter of my life (education).”

&gt; I would like to thank everyone for your care and support, be it writing letters, showing support on X, or in any other form. They all mean a lot to me and keep me strong. I will do my time, conclude this phase and focus on the next chapter of my life (education).
&gt; 
&gt; I will remain a…
&gt; 
&gt; — CZ 🔶 BNB (@cz\_binance) [May 1, 2024](https://twitter.com/cz_binance/status/1785465555899822488?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw)

While awaiting sentencing in the US, CZ had already set in motion Giggle Academy, a [free basic education platform](https://dailycoin.com/ex-binance-chief-changpeng-zhao-teases-new-educational-project/) for young students. Notably, it will not feature any cryptocurrency-related content.

The former Binance CEO thanked those who supported him during this ordeal. He stated that the messages of support and backing kept him strong through this uncertain period of his life.

Despite the prison sentence, many in the crypto industry consider CZ a victim of the “[war on crypto](https://dailycoin.com/sec-chair-gensler-defends-crypto-crackdown/)” by US authorities. His guilty plea to money laundering violations enabled Binance to avoid further enforcement actions.

However, in delivering the sentence, Judge Jones clarified that CZ is responsible for Binance’s compliance failings.

CZ Expresses Regret 
--------------------

In handing down sentencing, [Judge Jones stated](https://www.cnbc.com/2024/04/30/binance-founder-changpeng-zhao-cz-sentenced-to-four-months-in-prison-.html) that CZ had the “wherewithal, finance capabilities, and people power” to ensure Binance complied with money laundering regulations. However, the judge determined that CZ “failed at that opportunity.”

While prosecutors had pushed for a [three-year prison term](https://dailycoin.com/u-s-doj-asks-changpeng-zhao-cz-to-be-jailed-for-3-years/), Judge Jones opted to show a degree of leniency by handing down a four-month sentence instead. The relatively light punishment suggested the court recognized CZ’s conduct in trying to resolve the case as quickly as possible.

Addressing the court, CZ stated that the sentence represents “the first step of taking responsibility.” He admitted his failure to “implement an adequate anti-money laundering program” at Binance, stating, “I realize now the seriousness of that mistake.”

On the Flipside
---------------

*   **The average** **prison sentence** **for** **money laundering** **is** [**70 months**](https://www.ussc.gov/sites/default/files/pdf/research-and-publications/quick-facts/Money_Laundering_FY19.pdf)**, according to the** **US Sentencing Commission****.**
*   **Since the enforcement action,** **Binance****‘s global** **market share** **has** [**dropped to 55%**](https://www.binance.com/en/square/post/7165350385162)**.**

Why This Matters
----------------

As much as the crypto industry paints a picture of decentralization and operating independently of legacy systems, CZ’s sentencing is evidence that authorities can pull anyone back into their jurisdiction if they choose.

This article is for information purposes only and should not be considered trading or investment advice. Nothing herein shall be construed as financial, legal, or tax advice. Trading forex, cryptocurrencies, and CFDs pose a considerable risk of loss.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:46:00 GMT</pubDate><link>https://dailycoin.com/cz-vows-to-focus-on-next-chapter-after-sentencing/?utm_source=cryptopanic&amp;utm_medium=rss</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Cryptocurrency Cosmos Hub Rises More Than 6% In 24 hours

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554984/cryptocurrency-cosmos-hub-rises-more-than-6-in-24-hours

Published Time: 2024-05-01T11:00:11.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
Over the past 24 hours, **Cosmos Hub's** ATOM/USD price has risen 6.49% to **$8.31**. This is contrary to its negative trend over the past week where it has experienced a 2.0% loss, moving from $8.59 to its current price. As it stands right now, **the coin's all-time high is $44.45**.

The chart below compares the price movement and volatility for Cosmos Hub over the past 24 hours (left) to its price movement over the past week (right). The gray bands are Bollinger Bands, measuring the volatility for both the daily and weekly price movements. The wider the bands are, or the larger the gray area is at any given moment, the larger the volatility.

![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

Cosmos Hub's trading volume has climbed 140.0% over the past week along with the circulating supply of the coin, which has increased 0.05%. This brings the circulating supply to 390.69 million. According to our data, the current market cap ranking for ATOM is #31 at $3.25 billion.

![Image 2: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

[Powered by CoinGecko API](https://www.coingecko.com/en/api)

_This article was generated by Benzinga's automated content engine and reviewed by an editor._

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:46:25 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554984/cryptocurrency-cosmos-hub-rises-more-than-6-in-24-hours?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Super Micro Folly, Stock Market Direction Depends On Which Powell Shows Up – Objective Or Political - Sup

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/markets/24/05/38554907/super-micro-folly-stock-market-direction-depends-on-which-powell-shows-up-objective-or-political

Published Time: 2024-05-01T10:57:45.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
_To gain an edge, this is what you need to know today._

![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

### **Making A Fortune In Artificial Intelligence**

Please [click here](https://thearorareport.com/chart-analysis-stock-market-fomc-meeting-powell-rate-decision-smci-mc-05012024) for an enlarged chart of **Super Micro Computer Inc** SMCI.

Note the following:

*   This article is about the big picture, not an individual stock. The chart of SMCI stock is being used to illustrate the point.
*   Super Micro has been the most favorite artificial intelligence stock of the momo crowd. The chart shows the big drop in the stock on earnings released after the market closed.
*   The chart shows a 40.5% drop since the high in March.
*   RSI shown on the chart foretold what was to come.
*   The momo crowd, including momo gurus, that ran up the stock did not really understand the server business.
*   **SMCI presents an important learning moment for prudent investors. These are four important points here:**
*   **What you do not buy is as important as what you buy.**  
*   **A little knowledge is a dangerous thing.**  
*   **The momo crowd’s history is that they make money because they run up stocks with their own buying. Subsequently, the momo crowd loses money when smart money sells into the strength. Often, the momo crowd loses more money than they make, resulting in a net loss.**   
*   **Follow smart money for investments. Selectively follow the momo crowd for very short term trades when there is a Signal or Signal Limited.**  
*   Members and readers of The Arora Report, already knew in advance what was to come. On March 4, right near the top of SMCI stock, [we wrote](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/24/03/37461504/yolo-rears-its-ugly-head-in-the-stock-market-bitcoin-hits-65k-target-opec-extends-production-cuts):

*   &gt; SMCI has become a favorite of the momo crowd. The momo crowd incorrectly thinks SMCI has the same potential as Nvidia (NVDA). Investors need to keep in mind the following:

*   &gt; SMCI moves a lot more than NVDA. SMCI is so volatile because of the small float.

*   &gt; SMCI is an assembler of servers for artificial intelligence. It uses components from NVDA, Micron (MU), and Marvell (MRVL).

*   &gt; NVDA has a large moat to protect it that includes IP for its GPUs. SMCI has no moat and the barrier to entry for competitors is low.

*   &gt; SMCI sales are to hyperscalers like Microsoft (MSFT), Amazon (AMZN), and Google (GOOG). The reason SMCI sales are booming is that they have availability of NVDA chips. As chips become more available to competitors, SMCI will not be able to sustain its sales growth rate.

*   &gt; The momo crowd is buying SMCI due to lack of knowledge.  However, there are many investors who understand and have the knowledge of SMCI's business. Many such investors are short selling SMCI.  For the time being, short sellers are being overwhelmed by the YOLO crowd.

*   &gt; Taking all of the above into consideration with the [quantitative analysis screen](https://thearorareport.com/zyx-quantitative-screen) of the ZYX Change Method, in an optimistic case, the fair value of SMCI stock is $442 - $486.


*   You may recall that The Arora Report was the first one to identify that artificial intelligence was real in 2022. At that time, momo gurus were selling AI stock.
*   A fortune is to be made in AI between now and 2030.  SMCI shows that at times it will be treacherous. You need expert guidance.  Equally important is building your knowledge of investments in AI. 
*   **FOMC will release its decision at 2pm ET today. FOMC is expected to keep interest rates unchanged. The key event is Powell’s conference. The data shows that professional traders are expecting higher volatility during Powell’s conference than at any other point over the last year.** 
*   **In The Arora Report analysis, the near term direction of the stock market will come down to if objective Powell shows up or if political Powell shows up.**  
*   **If objective Powell shows up, expect the stock market to go down.  The reason is that the stock market is still levitating on hopium and not paying attention to the data.**  
*   **If political Powell shows up, expect a rip roaring rally.** 
*   We previously shared that prudent investors should pay attention to the Treasury refunding plan.
*   The Treasury plans to borrow $243B in the April to June quarter vs. $202B estimate.
*   The Treasury has just released the composition of the borrowing.
*   In The Arora Report analysis, the composition is more important than the increased amount of borrowing. Last time, the Treasury manipulated the borrowing to make stock and bond markets run higher. We will be carefully analyzing the just released new data.
*   Automatic Data Processing Inc ADP is the largest private payroll processor in the country.  It uses its data to give a glimpse of the jobs picture in advance of the official jobs report that will be released on Friday at 8:30am ET.  ADP employment change came at 192K vs. 175K consensus.  This indicates that the jobs picture is staying very strong.  In The Arora Report analysis, the strength is at the low end while the job picture remains weak in IT and finance.

### **Magnificent Seven Money Flows**

In the early trade, money flows are positive in **Amazon.com, Inc.** AMZN, **Alphabet Inc Class C** GOOG, and **Microsoft Corp** MSFT.

In the early trade, money flows are neutral in **Meta Platforms Inc** META.

In the early trade, money flows are negative in **Apple Inc** AAPL, **NVIDIA Corp** NVDA, and **Tesla Inc** TSLA.

In the early trade, money flows are negative in **SPDR S&amp;P 500 ETF Trust** SPY and **Invesco QQQ Trust Series 1** QQQ.

### **Momo Crowd And Smart Money In Stocks**

The momo crowd is buying stocks in the early trade. Smart money is inactive in the early trade.

### **Gold**

The momo crowd is buying gold in the early trade.  Smart money is inactive in the early trade.

For longer-term, please see gold and silver ratings.

The most popular ETF for gold is **SPDR Gold Trust** GLD. The most popular ETF for silver is **iShares Silver Trust** SLV. 

### **Oil**

The momo crowd is selling oil in the early trade.  Smart money is inactive in the early trade.

For longer-term, please see oil ratings.

The most popular ETF for oil is **United States Oil ETF** USO.

### **Bitcoin**

**Bitcoin** BTC/USD has fallen below $60,000 on momo crowd selling.  Recent momo crowd bitcoin buyers who fell prey to whales’ propaganda of buying on bitcoin halving and bought bitcoin above $70,000 are panicking and selling. Of course, if you listened to the podcast on bitcoin halving, you knew in advance that this was a high probability outcome.

### **Protection Band And What To Do Now**

It is important for investors to look ahead and not in the rearview mirror.

Consider continuing to hold good, very long term, existing positions. Based on individual risk preference, consider a protection band consisting of cash or Treasury bills or short-term tactical trades as well as short to medium term hedges and short term hedges. This is a good way to protect yourself and participate in the upside at the same time.

You can determine your protection bands by adding cash to hedges. The high band of the protection is appropriate for those who are older or conservative. The low band of the protection is appropriate for those who are younger or aggressive. If you do not hedge, the total cash level should be more than stated above but significantly less than cash plus hedges.

**It is worth reminding that you cannot take advantage of new upcoming opportunities if you are not holding enough cash.**  When adjusting hedge levels, consider adjusting partial stop quantities for stock positions (non ETF); consider using wider stops on remaining quantities and also allowing more room for high beta stocks.  High beta stocks are the ones that move more than the market.

### **Traditional 60/40 Portfolio**

Probability based risk reward adjusted for inflation does not favor long duration strategic bond allocation at this time.

Those who want to stick to traditional 60% allocation to stocks and 40% to bonds may consider focusing on only high quality bonds and bonds of seven year duration or less. Those willing to bring sophistication to their investing may consider using bond ETFs as tactical positions and not strategic positions at this time.

**The Arora Report is known for its accurate calls. The Arora Report correctly called the big artificial intelligence rally before anyone else, the new bull market of 2023, the bear market of 2022, new stock market highs right after the virus low in 2020, the virus drop in 2020, the DJIA rally to 30,000 when it was trading at 16,000, the start of a mega bull market in 2009, and the financial crash of 2008. Please click here to sign up for a free forever [Generate Wealth Newsletter](https://thearorareport.com/generate-wealth-newsletter).**

_This article is from an unpaid external contributor. It does not represent Benzinga's reporting and has not been edited for content or accuracy._

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:46:50 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/24/05/38554907/super-micro-folly-stock-market-direction-depends-on-which-powell-shows-up-objective-or-political?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: How Bad Is Donald Trump's Crypto Portfolio Down With Bitcoin Below $58K?

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554649/how-bad-is-donald-trumps-crypto-portfolio-down-with-bitcoin-below-58k

Published Time: 2024-05-01T10:49:46.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
Former President **Donald Trump's** [crypto portfolio](https://www.benzinga.com/money/maga-trump-price-prediction) is taking a heavy hit, as **Bitcoin** plummeted below the $58,000 mark.

**What Happened:** Blockchain analytics firm Arkham Intelligence [data](https://platform.arkhamintelligence.com/explorer/entity/donald-trump) shows Donald Trump's wallet is currently valued at $5.17 million—meaning the former President’s portfolio has seens a drawdown of over $1 million in the last two days alone.

The largest holding of the portfolio is 579,290 tokens of **MAGA Memecoin** TRUMP/USD, valued at $2.48 million. The token is a meme coin that endorses Trump and has gained significant attention since launching last summer. When the project launched, the creators sent 580,000 TRUMP tokens to the former president’s wallet address.

Trump also holds 421.375 **Ethereum** ETH/USD, worth $1.22 million and 374.5 **WETH** WETH/USD, worth $1.08 million.

[![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)](https://www.benzinga.com/events/digital-assets/)

_Also Read: [Donald Trump’s Crypto Investments Could Help Pay Back His $450M In Damages](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/04/38461151/donald-trumps-crypto-investments-could-help-pay-back-his-450m-in-damages)_

**Why It Matters:** Trump began take an interest in cryptocurrency in late 2022, when his name, image, and likeness were used to market and sell the [Trump Digital Trading Cards](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/04/38222451/original-trump-nft-collection-trading-volume-plunges-99-in-past-30-days-ahead-of-criminal-) non-fungible token (NFT) collection.

Since its launch in September 2023, the TRUMP meme coin has rocketed to an all-time high of over $400 million in market capitalization but has lost over 50% of its value from that peak.

Whether Trump will sell his portfolio to realize losses is unknown. However, Trump has said he has “fun” with “[crazy new currencies](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/04/38530092/donald-trump-says-he-has-fun-with-crypto-despite-losing-over-3-million-in-60-days)“—albeit that was during more favorable market conditions. 

**What's Next**: The influence of meme coins and [Bitcoin as an institutional asset class](https://www.benzinga.com/money/is-bitcoin-a-good-investment) are topics expected to be thoroughly explored at Benzinga's upcoming [Future of Digital Assets](https://www.benzinga.com/events/digital-assets/agenda/) event on Nov. 19.

_Read Next: [Donald Trump’s $5.7 Million Crypto Portfolio: How Many Cryptocurrencies Does Trump Own?](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/04/38338096/donald-trumps-5-7-million-crypto-portfolio-how-many-cryptocurrencies-does-trump-own)_

_Image created using artificial intelligence with Midjourney._

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:47:16 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38554649/how-bad-is-donald-trumps-crypto-portfolio-down-with-bitcoin-below-58k?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Tether just obliterated its former net profit record for a single quarter

URL Source: https://blockworks.co/news/tether-smashes-former-net-profit-record

Markdown Content:
Stablecoin issuer Tether has notched a record quarterly net profit at a time during which the company is broadening its scope. 

Tether tallied an all-time high net profit of $4.52 billion in the first quarter, according to a Wednesday attestation report by auditing firm BDO. 

Tether’s first quarter net operating profits of $1 billion were driven by its US Treasury holdings, the company added. Other profits stemmed from mark-to-market gains in its bitcoin and gold positions.

Bitcoin’s price hit a new peak of about $73,000 in mid-March before trending downward in April.

The $4.52 billion total obliterates the former record of $2.85 billion in net profit gathered during the last three months of 2023.

**Read more:** [Tether made nearly $1B in monthly profit during Q4](https://blockworks.co/news/tether-monthly-profit-q4)

Tether’s token, [USDT](https://blockworks.co/tag/usdt), is intended to maintain a value of $1 and can be redeemed for US dollars at any time.  

As of March 31, [Tether](https://blockworks.co/tag/tether)’s reserves were nearly $6.3 billion higher than the liabilities of the companies issuing USDT.  

USDT’s market capitalization was roughly $110 billion at 10 am ET, behind only bitcoin and ether among crypto assets. That figure is more than triple the $33 billion market cap of competing stablecoin USDC. 

The latest disclosure comes as Tether seeks to build out its business beyond just [stablecoins](https://blockworks.co/tag/stablecoins).

**Read more:** [Tether looks to ‘build the next generation of open AI models’ with new data division](https://blockworks.co/news/tether-hiring-ai-division-jobs)

It recently launched a data initiative focused on developing and investing in new technology, for example. Other new divisions include a unit focused on blockchain-based financial infrastructure and one involved in the [mining](https://blockworks.co/tag/mining) and energy sectors. 

“With this evolution beyond our traditional stablecoin offerings, we are ready to build and support the invention and implementation of cutting-edge technology that removes the limitations of what’s possible in this world,” CEO Paolo Ardoino said in a statement last month.

* * *

**Start your day with top crypto insights from David Canellis and Katherine Ross. [Subscribe to the Empire newsletter](https://blockworks.co/newsletter/empire).**

Tags

*   [earnings](https://blockworks.co/tag/earnings)
*   [stablecoins](https://blockworks.co/tag/stablecoins)
*   [Tether](https://blockworks.co/tag/tether)
*   [USDT](https://blockworks.co/tag/usdt)
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:47:39 GMT</pubDate><link>https://blockworks.co/news/tether-smashes-former-net-profit-record</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Bitvavo taps Figment to enhance staking services in Europe - CoinJournal

URL Source: https://coinjournal.net/news/bitvavo-taps-figment-to-enhance-staking-services-in-europe/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:26:35+00:00

Markdown Content:
![Image 1: Bitvavo taps Figment to enhance staking services in Europe](https://coinjournal.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/Bitvavo-taps-Figment-to-enhance-staking-services-in-Europe.jpg)

*   The partnership between Figment and Bitvavo underscores the growing significance of staking services in the cryptocurrency industry.
*   Both entities aim to unlock new opportunities and enhance the overall user experience by combining their expertise and resources.
*   With Bitvavo’s expansive reach and Figment’s proven track record in staking infrastructure, the collaboration is poised to reshape the landscape of staking services in Europe.

Netherlands-based cryptocurrency exchange [Bitvavo](https://coinjournal.net/exchanges/bitvavo/) is set to bolster its staking services across Europe through a strategic partnership with institutional staking platform Figment.

With a user base exceeding 1.5 million in the Benelux region, Bitvavo aims to elevate its offerings, tapping into Figment’s expertise and infrastructure to provide enhanced staking capabilities to its customers.

Expanding staking services with Figment
---------------------------------------

The partnership between Figment and Bitvavo signifies a strategic move towards offering additional security measures and expanding staking opportunities.

Bitvavo CEO Mark Nuvelstijn underscored the importance of staking in the cryptocurrency landscape, recognizing it as a vital service for their vast user base.

By collaborating with Figment, a prominent player in staking infrastructure, Bitvavo aims to fortify the security and reliability of its staking services. Figment’s comprehensive market knowledge and track record position them as a valuable partner in this endeavour.

Leveraging Figment’s institutional-grade infrastructure, the Dutch-based crypto exchange will stake user assets across multiple proof-of-stake protocols, including [Ethereum](https://coinjournal.net/ethereum/what-is-ethereum/), Solana, and [NEAR Protocol](https://coinjournal.net/near-protocol/what-is-near-protocol/).

Bitvavo’s European expansion
----------------------------

Bitvavo’s expansion into Europe has been marked by steady progress and regulatory compliance.

Following regulatory approval to operate in Austria, Bitvavo successfully launched its services in Italy in 2022.

In addition, the recent approval from France’s Autorité des Marchés Financiers (AMF) enabled Bitvavo to extend its offerings to French users.

These expansions align with Bitvavo’s commitment to providing accessible and compliant cryptocurrency services across Europe.

* * *

###### Share this article

* * *

###### Categories

* * *

###### Tags
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:36:52 GMT</pubDate><link>https://coinjournal.net/news/bitvavo-taps-figment-to-enhance-staking-services-in-europe/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Bitcoin down 20%+ from all-time highs — Is BTC price headed to $50K?

URL Source: https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-down-21-all-time-high-50k-btc-next

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:21:51.000Z

Markdown Content:
While the current correction remains in line with historical price corrections, Bitcoin could briefly fall to the $50,000 mark after losing the average ETF inflow mark of $59,000.

1828 Total views

16 Total shares

![Image 1: Bitcoin down 20%+ from all-time highs — Is BTC price headed to $50K?](https://images.cointelegraph.com/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=90,width=1434/https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/26b87a55-25d1-4975-b34c-820250196d2d.jpg)

Own this piece of crypto history

[Collect this article as NFT](https://mint.cointelegraph.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcointelegraph.com%2Fnews%2Fbitcoin-down-21-all-time-high-50k-btc-next&amp;utm_source=cointelegraph_com&amp;utm_medium=button&amp;utm_campaign=articles)

Bitcoin’s price is down around 21% from its all-time high. But while this remains in line with previous bull market corrections, Bitcoin could still fall to the $50,000 mark in the near term, based on historic patterns. 

BTC is down 25% from its all-time high
--------------------------------------

Bitcoin ([BTC](https://cointelegraph.com/bitcoin-price)) price fell over 12% on the weekly chart to $57,780 as of 1:10 p.m. in UTC, which is 21.6% lower thatn its all-time high of $73,750, reached on March 14, according to [CoinMarketCap](https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/bitcoin/) data.

![Image 2: btc - btc - btc - btc - btc -](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/123a2271-0bf6-4bcc-8aa3-0cfc3c68ae5a.png)

_BTC/USDT, 1-day chart. Source: CoinMarketCap_

The current correction is the deepest retrace of this cycle, according to popular Bitcoin analyst Rekt Capital, who [wrote](https://twitter.com/rektcapital/status/1785592568048140451) in a May 1 X post:

&gt; “This current retrace is officially the deepest (-23.6%), recently eclipsing the -22.9% retrace from early 2023. \[…\] Bitcoin has already eclipsed the deepest retrace in the cycle and is 13 days away from equalling the longest retrace in this cycle as well.” The pullback is 48 days long, compared to the longest retrace of 63 days during this cycle. ![Image 3: a chart of the ecb - gbp - gbp - gbp -](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/d74c32fc-4617-4950-b112-a7839cf81749.jpeg)

_BTC/USD, 1-week chart. Source:_ _Rekt Capital_

Similar corrections have occurred during previous Bitcoin rallies. During the 2018 bull run, Bitcoin saw five corrections of over 30% and an additional 29% correction, according to pseudonymous Bitcoin trader Sister Laura’s April 30 X [post](https://twitter.com/DecrimNat/status/1785366854602801565):

![Image 4](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/71b0b0a5-8889-4992-bb9f-812bf53c4c12.jpeg)

_BTC/USD, 1-week chart. 2016-2018, Source:_ _Sister Laura_

**_Related:_** [**_Tether nets record $4.5B profit in Q1 2024 — majority from Bitcoin and gold_**](https://cointelegraph.com/news/tether-record-4-52-billion-profit-q1-2024)

Can Bitcoin dip to $50,000 in the short term?
---------------------------------------------

Bitcoin lost a significant support level at the $59,000 mark, which also acted as the short-term holder realized price (STH-RP), or the average inflow price of the spot Bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs).

Losing the $59,000 mark could lead to Bitcoin revisiting the $50,000 mark, according to Jag Kooner, head of derivatives at Bitfinex. He told Cointelegraph:

&gt; “While price predictions are not appropriate based on these, the STH-RP is a crucial support level for BTC to hold and on losing it, or the average ETF buyer cost basis, there is a high likelihood that there is a cascade down to low $50,000s.”

Over $750 million worth of cumulative leveraged long positions would be liquidated across all exchanges if Bitcoin’s price fell below $60,000, according to [Coinglass](https://www.coinglass.com/pro/futures/LiquidationMap).

![Image 5: a graph showing the spread of the stock market](https://s3.cointelegraph.com/uploads/2024-05/867aab98-b85e-40f1-b54e-c5356361bc1c.png)

_Bitcoin exchange liquidation map. Source: Coinglass_

Bitcoin price fell below the $60,000 mark days after the debut of the first spot [Bitcoin ETFs in Hong Kong](https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-sell-news-hong-kong-etf-launch-btc-60k), which amassed $12.4 million in daily trading volume during the first day.

The debut of the Hong Kong ETFs generated lower-than-expected trading volumes due to the difficult macroeconomic conditions, according to James Wo, the founder and CEO of DFG.

Wo told Cointelegraph:

&gt; "These ETFs were launched in different market conditions. U.S. ETFs were launched earlier this year when the market was pricing in around six rate cuts in 2024. Given the sticky inflation data, markets are now pricing in only one rate cut, which saw crypto prices tumbling recently.”

**_Related:_** [**_Bitcoin outperforms Tesla stock for the first time since 2019_**](https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-outpeforms-tesla-stock-first-time-since-2019)

This article does not contain investment advice or recommendations. Every investment and trading move involves risk, and readers should conduct their own research when making a decision.

![Image 6: a blue and yellow emoji with a smiley face](https://images.cointelegraph.com/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=90,width=72/https://s3.cointelegraph.com/storage/uploads/view/c3bc0490407720f59d1c058d0a2788ce.png) 3![Image 7: an image of a rocket ship flying through the air](https://images.cointelegraph.com/cdn-cgi/image/format=auto,onerror=redirect,quality=90,width=72/https://s3.cointelegraph.com/storage/uploads/view/5886af490e0311fa1838e13f042f28e5.png) 1

![Image 8](https://zoa.cointelegraph.com/pixel?postId=129094&amp;regionId=1)
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:37:26 GMT</pubDate><link>https://cointelegraph.com/news/bitcoin-down-21-all-time-high-50k-btc-next</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Elliptic's AI-driven research helps fight Bitcoin money laundering

URL Source: https://cryptobriefing.com/elliptic-ai-crypto-crime-detection/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:17:24+00:00

Markdown Content:
Deep learning model identifies new money laundering behaviors to enhance Elliptic's crypto transaction monitoring
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Blockchain analytics firm Elliptic has made significant progress in using artificial intelligence (AI) to identify potential money laundering patterns on the Bitcoin blockchain.

In a [research paper](https://www.elliptic.co/blog/our-new-research-enhancing-blockchain-analytics-through-ai) co-authored with the MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab, Elliptic described its use of a deep learning model trained on a dataset of nearly 200 million transactions to detect illicit activity involving groups of bitcoin nodes and transaction chains.

The research builds upon a previous study conducted in 2019, which utilized a much smaller dataset of 200,000 transactions. The new “Elliptic2” dataset contains 122,000 labeled “subgraphs,” representing groups of connected nodes and transaction chains known to have links to illicit activity. By training the AI model on this extensive dataset, [Elliptic](https://cryptobriefing.com/elliptic-estimates-12b-lost-to-defi-exploits/) aims to improve the accuracy and efficiency of detecting [money laundering](https://cryptobriefing.com/usdt-usage-money-laundering-surges-east-southeast-asia-un-report/) and other financial crimes on the blockchain.

[![Image 1: Sapphire](https://static.cryptobriefing.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/18060845/600x500.jpg)](https://sapphire.cryptobriefing.com/?utm_source=cryptobriefing&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=180324&amp;ap=mreciad&amp;offer=x240415070T0U7V)

The inherent transparency of blockchain data makes it well-suited for machine learning techniques, as transaction information and entity types can be readily analyzed. This stands in contrast to traditional finance, where transaction data is often siloed, making the application of [AI](https://cryptobriefing.com/ai/) more challenging.

The trained model successfully identified proceeds of crime deposited at a crypto exchange, as well as novel money laundering transaction patterns and previously-unknown illicit wallets. These findings are already being incorporated into Elliptic’s products to enhance their capabilities.

&gt; “The money laundering techniques identified by the model have been identified because they are prevalent in bitcoin,” Elliptic co-founder Tom Robinson explained in an email. “Crypto laundering practices will evolve over time as they cease being effective, but an advantage of an AI/deep learning approach is that new money laundering patterns are identified automatically as they emerge.”

The research revealed common money laundering techniques, such as “peeling chains,” where a user sends cryptocurrency to a destination address while sending the remainder to another address under their control, forming a chain of transactions. Another prevalent method involved the use of “nested services,” businesses that move funds through accounts at larger crypto exchanges, sometimes even without the exchange’s knowledge or approval.

To encourage further collaboration and advancement in this field, Elliptic has made the “Elliptic2” dataset publicly available. As the largest public dataset of its kind, it will enable the wider community to develop new AI techniques for detecting illicit cryptocurrency transactions and contribute to the ongoing fight against financial crime in the crypto space.

The information on or accessed through this website is obtained from independent sources we believe to be accurate and reliable, but Decentral Media, Inc. makes no representation or warranty as to the timeliness, completeness, or accuracy of any information on or accessed through this website. Decentral Media, Inc. is not an investment advisor. We do not give personalized investment advice or other financial advice. The information on this website is subject to change without notice. Some or all of the information on this website may become outdated, or it may be or become incomplete or inaccurate. We may, but are not obligated to, update any outdated, incomplete, or inaccurate information.

Crypto Briefing may augment articles with AI-generated content created by Crypto Briefing’s own proprietary AI platform. We use AI as a tool to deliver fast, valuable and actionable information without losing the insight - and oversight - of experienced crypto natives. All AI augmented content is carefully reviewed, including for factural accuracy, by our editors and writers, and always draws from multiple primary and secondary sources when available to create our stories and articles.

You should never make an investment decision on an ICO, IEO, or other investment based on the information on this website, and you should never interpret or otherwise rely on any of the information on this website as investment advice. We strongly recommend that you consult a licensed investment advisor or other qualified financial professional if you are seeking investment advice on an ICO, IEO, or other investment. We do not accept compensation in any form for analyzing or reporting on any ICO, IEO, cryptocurrency, currency, tokenized sales, securities, or commodities.

See [full terms and conditions](https://cryptobriefing.com/terms-and-conditions).
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:37:48 GMT</pubDate><link>https://cryptobriefing.com/elliptic-ai-crypto-crime-detection/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Cryptocurrency Cronos Decreases More Than 6% Within 24 hours

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38555194/cryptocurrency-cronos-decreases-more-than-6-within-24-hours

Published Time: 2024-05-01T11:03:50.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
**Cronos's** CRO/USD price has decreased 6.74% over the past 24 hours to **$0.12**, continuing its downward trend over the past week of -1.0%, moving from $0.13 to its current price.

The chart below compares the price movement and volatility for Cronos over the past 24 hours (left) to its price movement over the past week (right). The gray bands are Bollinger Bands, measuring the volatility for both the daily and weekly price movements. The wider the bands are, or the larger the gray area is at any given moment, the larger the volatility.

![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

Cronos's trading volume has climbed 219.0% over the past week, moving in tandem, directionally, with the overall circulating supply of the coin, which has increased 0.12%. This brings the circulating supply to 26.70 billion. According to our data, the current market cap ranking for CRO is #30 at $3.26 billion.

![Image 2: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

[Powered by CoinGecko API](https://www.coingecko.com/en/api)

_This article was generated by Benzinga's automated content engine and reviewed by an editor._

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:38:38 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38555194/cryptocurrency-cronos-decreases-more-than-6-within-24-hours?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Cryptocurrency Ethereum Classic Falls More Than 3% In 24 hours

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38555167/cryptocurrency-ethereum-classic-falls-more-than-3-in-24-hours

Published Time: 2024-05-01T11:02:40.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
**Ethereum Classic's** ETC/USD price has decreased 3.19% over the past 24 hours to **$24.78**, continuing its downward trend over the past week of -9.0%, moving from $27.24 to its current price.

The chart below compares the price movement and volatility for Ethereum Classic over the past 24 hours (left) to its price movement over the past week (right). The gray bands are Bollinger Bands, measuring the volatility for both the daily and weekly price movements. The wider the bands are, or the larger the gray area is at any given moment, the larger the volatility.

![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

Ethereum Classic's trading volume has climbed 70.0% over the past week along with the circulating supply of the coin, which has increased 0.17%. This brings the circulating supply to 146.83 million, which makes up an estimated 69.69% of its max supply of 210.70 million. According to our data, the current market cap ranking for ETC is #28 at $3.62 billion.

![Image 2: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

[Powered by CoinGecko API](https://www.coingecko.com/en/api)

_This article was generated by Benzinga's automated content engine and reviewed by an editor._

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:39:01 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38555167/cryptocurrency-ethereum-classic-falls-more-than-3-in-24-hours?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Cryptocurrency Uniswap Falls More Than 4% In 24 hours

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38555126/cryptocurrency-uniswap-falls-more-than-4-in-24-hours

Published Time: 2024-05-01T11:01:21.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
Over the past 24 hours, **Uniswap's** UNI/USD price has fallen 4.7% to **$6.84**. This continues its negative trend over the past week where it has experienced a 12.0% loss, moving from $7.79 to its current price.

The chart below compares the price movement and volatility for Uniswap over the past 24 hours (left) to its price movement over the past week (right). The gray bands are Bollinger Bands, measuring the volatility for both the daily and weekly price movements. The wider the bands are, or the larger the gray area is at any given moment, the larger the volatility.

![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

**The trading volume for the coin has increased 46.0%** over the past week while the overall circulating supply of the coin has increased 0.03% to over 753.77 million which makes up an estimated 75.38% of its max supply, which is 1.00 billion. The current market cap ranking for **UNI** is **#25** at **$5.15 billion**.

![Image 2: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

[Powered by CoinGecko API](https://www.coingecko.com/en/api)

_This article was generated by Benzinga's automated content engine and reviewed by an editor._

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:39:49 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/insights/cryptocurrency/24/05/38555126/cryptocurrency-uniswap-falls-more-than-4-in-24-hours?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: SEC Repels Ripple's Challenge in Contested Witness Dispute: Is It Summary Evidence or Undisclosed Expertise?

URL Source: https://dailycoin.com/sec-repels-ripples-challenge-in-contested-witness-dispute/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T16:00:00+00:00

Markdown Content:
SEC and Ripple Labs have clashed over the admissibility of an SEC accountant’s testimony in their ongoing legal battle.

*   [![Image 1: Kyle Calvert](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Kyle-Calvert-50x50.png)](https://dailycoin.com/author/kyle-calvert/"KyleCalvert")


by Fact checked by: [Ciaran Lawler](https://dailycoin.com/author/ciaran-lawler/"Factcheckedby:CiaranLawler"), Editor: [Stefan Trapp](https://dailycoin.com/author/stefan-trapp/"Editor:StefanTrapp")

Published: May 1, 2024 │ 4:00 PM GMT

![Image 2: Big suited man staring at a giant XRP coin in space.](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/XRP_Ripple_SEC_Banker_Institutional_Space_Coin_Hugr_web.jpg)

_Created by Gabor Kovacs from DailyCoin_

[![Image 3: Google News Follow Button](https://dailycoin.com/wp-content/themes/cryptotimes/assets/img/follow-google-news-dailycoin-cryptonews.png)](https://news.google.com/publications/CAAqBwgKMIjkmAswmO6wAw?ceid=IN:en&amp;oc=3)

*   **The SEC and Ripple Labs have clashed over the validity of an accountant’s testimony in their ongoing lawsuit.**
*   **The SEC has defended her role of summarizing financial data, which is a permissible practice within legal boundaries.**
*   **The dispute has hinged on whether the accountant stuck to basic calculations or delved into expert analysis.**

The [ongoing legal battle](https://dailycoin.com/sec-vs-ripple-will-lawsuit-decide-fate-crypto-industry/) between the [SEC](https://dailycoin.com/sec-and-crypto-us-regulator-influence-on-cryptocurrency/) and [Ripple Labs](https://dailycoin.com/ripple-xrp-xrp-industry-leader-or-cryptocurrency-dinosaur/) took a new turn as the SEC responded to Ripple’s challenge regarding the testimony of SEC accountant Andrea Fox. Ripple had sought to dismiss Fox’s declaration, arguing it constituted undisclosed expert testimony. 

Ripple and SEC Clash Over Expert Witness Status
-----------------------------------------------

The SEC [strongly disagrees](https://twitter.com/FilanLaw/status/1785026413357105401), defending her work as a permissible form of summary evidence under established legal rules. The crux of the dispute lies in the nature of Fox’s contribution. Ripple contends that her role went beyond mere summarization, involving financial analysis and critical decisions about categorizing Ripple’s financial data. 

This, [according to Ripple](https://twitter.com/FilanLaw/status/1782578348423573898), necessitates disclosure as expert testimony. The SEC counters this claim, maintaining that Fox’s calculations are straightforward and lack the elements of expert analysis. They argue that her work involved no specialized skills or subjective opinions, simply basic calculations derived from Ripple’s financial records.

In their defense, the SEC emphasizes that Fox’s role was to simplify large volumes of financial data for the court’s benefit. They assert that using assumptions while handling such data is standard practice for summary witnesses and doesn’t elevate the evidence to the level of expert analysis.

The SEC further bolsters its argument by citing legal precedents that establish summary witnesses’ acceptable use of assumptions in court proceedings. They maintain that Fox’s work falls squarely within the established parameters of a summary witness as outlined by relevant legal procedures, which clearly define expert witnesses as those providing specialized knowledge.

Narrow Focus Raises Concerns About Industry Regulation
------------------------------------------------------

While the SEC aims to uphold the legitimacy of Fox’s contribution, the case has drawn criticism for its seemingly narrow focus. Some argue that the SEC prioritizes investor protection against missed profit opportunities over addressing broader systemic issues within the cryptocurrency landscape, as highlighted by the recent [FTX collapse](https://dailycoin.com/sam-bankman-fried-cryptos-fallen-hero/). 

This incident has reignited concerns about the SEC’s effectiveness in regulating the rapidly evolving cryptocurrency market. The outcome of this legal battle will likely have significant implications for the future of cryptocurrency regulation and the SEC’s approach to navigating the complexities of this dynamic industry.

On the Flipside
---------------

*   **The SEC argues that Andrea Fox’s work simply summarized financial data and lacked the complexity of expert analysis.**
*   **They maintain Fox’s role falls within the legal definition of a summary witness, distinct from experts providing specialized knowledge.**

Why This Matters
----------------

This legal battle between the SEC and Ripple hinges on the definition of “expert testimony” within cryptocurrency regulation. The outcome will set a precedent for how the SEC evaluates evidence in future crypto-related cases, potentially impacting the regulatory landscape for the entire industry.

This article is for information purposes only and should not be considered trading or investment advice. Nothing herein shall be construed as financial, legal, or tax advice. Trading forex, cryptocurrencies, and CFDs pose a considerable risk of loss.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:40:13 GMT</pubDate><link>https://dailycoin.com/sec-repels-ripples-challenge-in-contested-witness-dispute/?utm_source=cryptopanic&amp;utm_medium=rss</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Bitcoin's Price Swings:  Here is Why BTC Market is Highly Volatile

URL Source: https://coinedition.com/bitcoins-price-swings-here-is-why-btc-market-is-highly-volatile/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T16:05:00+00:00

Markdown Content:
Published: May 1, 2024

Last Updated: May 1, 2024

*   **Bitcoin’s volatility stems from its young existence, scarcity factor, and influence of large-scale investors.**
*   **Liquidity issues in the cryptocurrency market exacerbate Bitcoin’s price swings.**
*   **Regulatory developments and the introduction of financial products may mitigate Bitcoin’s volatility in the future.**

[Bitcoin](https://coinedition.com/bitcoin-holds-steady-at-62k-can-bulls-push-past-72k-resistance/?utm_source=telegram_channel&amp;utm_medium=referral) still astounds the financial area with its thrilling price alterations. From its early ages of few cents even per coin to today’s highs reaching more than $74,000, Bitcoin’s journey has been nothing short of remarkable. 

However, this journey has been marked by extreme volatility, with fluctuations of over 80% in value at times. Uncovering the origin of Bitcoin’s volatile nature is crucial for the success of investors and analysts as well, because that can give an indication of the future of cryptocurrencies.

The Bitcoin volatility is rooted in a diverse range of factors which take beginnings in the characteristic of the digital currency that is very young. Unlike the aged traditional assets that have a centuries-long historical data, Bitcoin and the broader cryptocurrency market are unable to maintain stability that comes from decades of influence of established market dynamics.

This first stage of the cryptocurrency development model leads to the permanent process of price discovery, when the value of Bitcoin is regularly reassessed by the market, which results in great price fluctuations in reaction on new information and happenings.

One of the fundamental contributors to Bitcoin’s volatility is its [fixed](https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/23311975.2021.1984624) supply cap of 21 million coins. This inherent scarcity factor can magnify price fluctuations as demand fluctuates against the unyielding supply limit. Additionally, the influence of large-scale investors, commonly referred to as “whales,” further exacerbates price volatility. Their substantial holdings allow them to sway market dynamics with significant buy or sell orders, leading to abrupt price changes.

Furthermore, the immaturity of the [cryptocurrency market](https://coinedition.com/market/) infrastructure introduces liquidity issues, wherein the capacity to execute large trades without impacting market prices is limited compared to more established markets. This lack of liquidity can intensify price swings as investors maneuver in and out of positions.

With the development of the cryptocurrency environment and regulatory frameworks taking shape, things might be changing for Bitcoin, which may moderate its volatility overtime. The emergence of Bitcoin-related derivatives shown in [spot ETFs](https://coinedition.com/bitcoin-etfs-promising-opportunities-and-potential-pitfalls-for-investors/) and the evolution of market infrastructure could make the trading process more stable.

**_Disclaimer:_** _The information presented in this article is for informational and educational purposes only. The article does not constitute financial advice or advice of any kind. Coin Edition is not responsible for any losses incurred as a result of the utilization of content, products, or services mentioned. Readers are advised to exercise caution before taking any action related to the company._
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:40:36 GMT</pubDate><link>https://coinedition.com/bitcoins-price-swings-here-is-why-btc-market-is-highly-volatile/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Tron (TRX) Founder Justin Sun Announces His Three Favorite Mem Tokens!

URL Source: https://en.bitcoinsistemi.com/tron-trx-founder-justin-sun-announces-his-three-favorite-mem-tokens/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T16:03:06+00:00

Markdown Content:
Tron (TRX) founder Justin Sun, who has recently been talked about with his Ethereum (ETH) purchases, spoke highly of Dogecoin (DOGE), Shiba Inu (SHIB) and Floki (FLOKI).

Tron (TRX) founder Justin Sun, who has been talked about recently with large amounts of Ethereum (ETH) purchases, this time came to the fore with the mem token announcement.

Justin Sun, who shared the part of his speech about mem tokens at the Token 2049 conference from his account X, spoke highly of mem tokens.

At this point, mentioning Dogecoin (DOGE), Shiba Inu (SHIB) and Floki (FLOKI), Sun said that he believes that meme tokens are the “first thing” that distinguishes the cryptocurrency industry from traditional finance.

Pointing out that Mem tokens will never disappear, Sun underlined that launching a successful Mem Token is “as difficult as creating a good crypto project.”

Additionally, the Tron founder argued that there is significant community support behind the success of meme tokens, and he also pointed to popular personalities who support them.

Citing Elon Musk, known for his support of Dogecoin, as an example, Sun said that DOGE and similar mem tokens with significant support will be very successful in the future.

Finally, Justin Sun described DOGE as one of the best cryptocurrency brands and reminded them of their potential in bull rallies.

&gt; Meme coins may seem unconventional, but they highlight the power of community in crypto. Building a successful project, meme-based or not, takes dedication.
&gt; 
&gt; Let’s see what the next bull cycle brings! 👀 [pic.twitter.com/S40tXLhSO3](https://t.co/S40tXLhSO3)
&gt; 
&gt; — H.E. Justin Sun 孙宇晨 (@justinsuntron) [May 1, 2024](https://twitter.com/justinsuntron/status/1785536405571309775?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw)

\*This is not investment advice.

Follow our [**Telegram**](https://t.me/btcsistemien) and **[Twitter](https://twitter.com/btcsistemiEN)** account now for exclusive news, analytics and on-chain data!
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:41:01 GMT</pubDate><link>https://en.bitcoinsistemi.com/tron-trx-founder-justin-sun-announces-his-three-favorite-mem-tokens/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Redstone Network Launches to Power Fully On-Chain Ethereum Games

URL Source: https://decrypt.co/229005/redstone-network-launches-fully-on-chain-ethereum-games

Published Time: 2024-05-01T16:01:05

Markdown Content:
[Redstone](https://redstone.xyz/), a new [Ethereum](https://decrypt.co/resources/what-is-ethereum-quickly-explained-four-minute-guide) scaling network designed for fully on-chain games and “autonomous worlds,” launched its mainnet today—with a number of early games already available for play.

Developed by Ethereum startup [Lattice](https://lattice.xyz/), Redstone was built via [Optimism](https://decrypt.co/resources/what-is-optimism-using-rollups-to-help-scale-ethereum)’s OP Stack scaling tech. But it’s much more than a rebranded riff on the layer-2 tech that also powers networks like [Base](https://decrypt.co/resources/what-is-base-coinbases-layer-2-chain) and [Zora](https://decrypt.co/145650/zora-launches-layer-2-nft-netowrk-battle-ethereum-gas-fees)—Redstone has been significantly retooled for the needs and demands of video games, particularly those that use blockchain for much more than asset ownership.

“We've had core developers come along and make really cool contributions to the OP Stack,” Optimism co-founder Ben Jones told _Decrypt_’s GG. “This is the first \[network\] that’s not just tweaking dials a little bit.” Many crypto or “Web3” games utilize technologies like NFTs for unique user-owned items or cryptocurrencies for decentralized economies. But fully on-chain or autonomous games also put their game logic or rules on-chain, working within the capabilities but also limitations of the decentralized technology to power playable games. “Most of the time, when you fully embrace the medium or the system you're building to, you tend to get more interesting results—and sometimes better harmonization—just purely from a product development perspective,” Lattice co-founder and CEO Justin Glibert told _Decrypt_’s GG. Glibert says his team has embraced this model of building entirely on Ethereum, a “computer that had to be multiplayer out of necessity, and not out of choice.” Following early experimental games like [Dark Forest](https://www.designboom.com/technology/dark-forest-one-of-a-kind-sci-fi-blockchain-game-cutting-edge-cryptography-brian-gu-gubsheep-11-15-2022/), zkDungeon, and OPCraft that his team created or helped build on other chains, they’ve designed Redstone to better suit such games—and it’s open to the public.

Certainly, crypto games can be built on layer-1 networks, as well as general-purpose layer-2 scaling networks. But fully on-chain games can be held back by the way those networks are typically designed. Games need low latency speeds, for example—and with such a constant flow of player inputs, they need to cut down on the friction of interacting with a blockchain.

Redstone is built for just that, and it also features the first implementation of Plasma Mode, an alternative data availability protocol co-developed by Lattice and OP Labs. Plasma Mode allows for increased transaction throughput via an [off-chain data availability provider](https://specs.optimism.io/experimental/plasma.html), but also includes a permissionless Ethereum layer-1 feature that lets any user challenge suspicious inputs.

In short, Plasma Mode picks different kinds of design trade-offs to power games and other high-throughput decentralized apps, but also includes an on-chain capability to challenge potential threats. It’s inspired by the [Plasma concept](https://plasma.io/plasma-deprecated.pdf) that Ethereum founder Vitalik Buterin co-authored back in 2017 (and recently [shined a fresh light on](https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2023/11/14/neoplasma.html)), and will be available throughout the OP Stack going forward.

That’s paired with MUD, Lattice’s engine for on-chain Ethereum games. It’s being used by the studio’s own Sky Strife, a tactical strategy game in the vein of Nintendo’s classic Advance Wars that’s available to play today. Other Redstone launch games also use MUD, plus EVE Online developer CCP Games is using the engine for its [Project Awakening game](https://decrypt.co/221814/project-awakening-preview-eve-online-crypto-game)—though Glibert said that CCP has yet to choose a network for that project.

Along with Sky Strife, the [initial lineup of Redstone games](https://community.redstone.xyz/) includes titles like [Biomes](https://twitter.com/biomesAW), a Minecraft-like sandbox game; [DF Ares](https://twitter.com/DFArchon), a community-driven revival of Dark Forest; and [Downstream](https://twitter.com/DownstreamGame), which has been described both as an “infinitely moddable MMO” and the “world's first post-singularity civilization simulator.”

![Image 1: A screenshot from Sky Strife](https://img.decrypt.co/insecure/rs:fit:3840:0:0:0/plain/https://cdn.decrypt.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/sky-strife.jpeg@webp)

A screenshot from Sky Strife. Image: Lattice

One of the more distinctive games on the launch list is [DEAR](https://twitter.com/dear_dyr), a game by ARPA that sounds like a cross between an abstract art project, a virtual pet simulator, and a crypto-fied social experiment. Or as an ARPA representative described it, “DEAR is a digital creature that transforms under the collective behavior of all players—a tug of war between two factions, whether you feed or abuse the creature.”

“Experimental” is a fair term to describe most of what’s happening around Redstone and fully on-chain games. Some of the early games look far from mass-market in aesthetic and are built around new and unfamiliar concepts.

There are various benefits to being fully on-chain, Glibert said, such as the ability to easily deploy modifications to games and create new business models around existing games. Fully on-chain games (FOCGs) can’t be shut down or erased from existence like some Web2 games, while autonomous worlds (AWs) could yield new kinds of play mechanics and experiences.

&gt; This onchain game introduces an interplay of LOVE and HATE, with a PVP twist.
&gt; 
&gt; DEAR gamer,
&gt; 
&gt; DEAR is a creature that inhabits a dark, digital forest, with cellular components woven into smart contracts. DEAR exhibits purposeful behaviour and mimics essential human interactions,… [pic.twitter.com/gRw2c5ucHc](https://t.co/gRw2c5ucHc)
&gt; 
&gt; — ggQuest (@gg\_quest\_gg) [April 24, 2024](https://twitter.com/gg_quest_gg/status/1783181178645725469?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw)

Whether there’s a business here, however, remains to be seen.

“Most of the studios out there that have raised capital to build on-chain games—nobody knows if it's actually going to be a valuable market,” said Glibert. “I would say most of the people that are doing this seriously, they also don't know if there's actually a mature-enough business model today to do it.”

But they’re still building, attempting to push the edges of what’s possible on-chain.

“There is a lot of noise of ‘how to monetize’ before a FOCG actually takes shape,” ARPA co-founder and CTO Majorknight told _Decrypt_’s GG. “Rushed monetization is the [killer of innovation](https://andrewkelley.me/post/why-we-cant-have-nice-software.html). At best, it creates one-hit-wonders like the [play-to-earn](https://decrypt.co/resources/what-are-play-to-earn-games-how-players-are-making-a-living-with-nfts) games we have seen and doesn't have anything to do with making FOCGs, or improving the infrastructure.”

Majorknight described the Lattice team as a team of “young, talented, and driven people who focus on building the infrastructure” for such games, further praising them for attempting to empower new types of on-chain games.

“The original vision of FOCGs is to utilize risk-free and creative scenarios to test the possibility of new blockchain applications and push the boundary of the infrastructure, similar to the relationship between games and simulations in science/engineering and between games and GPUs,” they added. “Who else to collaborate with if not the team who coined the term FOCG/AWs and established this vision beyond the short-sighted monetization?”

_Edited by [Stephen Graves](https://decrypt.co/author/stephengraves)_

### Stay on top of crypto news, get daily updates in your inbox.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:41:34 GMT</pubDate><link>https://decrypt.co/229005/redstone-network-launches-fully-on-chain-ethereum-games</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Bitcoin Greed No More: Sentiment Back At Neutral After $57,000 Plunge

URL Source: https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-greed-sentiment-neutral-57000-plunge/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T16:00:56Z

Markdown Content:
Data shows that Bitcoin sentiment has cooled off to neutral from greed following the asset’s latest plunge to the $57,000 level.

Bitcoin Fear &amp; Greed Index Has Returned To Neutral Levels
---------------------------------------------------------

The “[Fear &amp; Greed Index](https://www.newsbtc.com/crypto/why-crypto-fear-greed-index-sustainable-recovery/)” is an indicator created by [Alternative](https://alternative.me/crypto/fear-and-greed-index/) that shows the average sentiment among investors in the Bitcoin and wider cryptocurrency market.

This index estimates sentiment by considering five factors: volatility, trading volume, social media data, market cap dominance, and Google Trends.

![Image 1](https://servedbyadbutler.com/error/blank.gif)

[![Image 2: a gold and black poker chip with the words huge get bonus](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4118444)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2374568&amp;setID=366606&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=873125&amp;banID=521839794&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2293217&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714581695959086&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fbitcoin-news%2Fbitcoin-greed-sentiment-neutral-57000-plunge%2F&amp;hc=e82f54966e1de3211b3861befd9e926613b51c4b&amp;location=)

The metric uses a scale that runs from zero to 100 to represent this average sentiment. All values under 46 suggest that investors are fearful, while those above 54 imply a greedy market. The zone between these two cutoffs naturally corresponds to the territory of neutral mentality.

Now, here is what the Bitcoin sentiment looks like right now, according to the Fear &amp; Greed Index:

![Image 3: Bitcoin Fear &amp; Greed Index](https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/meter.png?w=367&amp;resize=367%2C332)

[![Image 4: a gold and black poker chip with the words huge get bonus](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4118444)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2374569&amp;setID=452518&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=873125&amp;banID=521839794&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2293218&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714581695958963&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fbitcoin-news%2Fbitcoin-greed-sentiment-neutral-57000-plunge%2F&amp;hc=4eacfdee76c3219845682d6bcb482aa3c92a0371&amp;location=)

The value of the metric appears to be 54 at the moment | Source: [Alternative](https://alternative.me/crypto/fear-and-greed-index/)

As displayed above, the Bitcoin Fear &amp; Greed Index is at a value of 54, implying that investors share a neutral sentiment currently. However, the neutrality is only just, as the metric is right at the boundary of the greed region.

This is a significant departure from yesterday’s sentiment: 67. The chart below shows how the indicator’s value has changed recently.

![Image 5: Bitcoin Neutral](https://www.newsbtc.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/chart.png?w=860&amp;resize=860%2C408)

[![Image 6: a gold and black poker chip with the words huge get bonus](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4118444)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2374570&amp;setID=452519&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=873125&amp;banID=521839794&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2293220&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714581696135905&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsbtc.com%2Fbitcoin-news%2Fbitcoin-greed-sentiment-neutral-57000-plunge%2F&amp;hc=268a890d886706066f2a7c7bb03ddd2dd6dc8db8&amp;location=)

The trend in the Fear &amp; Greed Index over the past year | Source: [Alternative](https://alternative.me/crypto/fear-and-greed-index/)

As the graph shows, the Bitcoin Fear &amp; Greed Index has been declining recently. For most of February and March, as well as the first half of April, the indicator was in or near a special zone called [extreme greed](https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-traders-no-extremely-greedy-rebound-signal/).

The market assumes this sentiment at values above 75. As the asset price struggled recently, the mentality cooled off from this extreme zone and entered the normal greed region. With the latest crash in BTC, the index has seen a sharp plunge, now exiting out of greed altogether.

Historically, cryptocurrency has tended to move against the majority’s expectations. The stronger this expectation, the higher the probability of such a contrary move.

This expectation is considered the strongest in extreme sentiment zones, as well as extreme fear and greed. As such, major bottoms and tops have often occurred in these territories.

The [all-time high (ATH) price](https://www.newsbtc.com/news/bitcoin-blasts-past-70000-in-wild-week-to-register-new-all-time-high/) last month, which continues to be the top of the rally so far, also occurred alongside extreme values of the Bitcoin Fear &amp; Greed Index.

With the sentiment now cooled to neutral, some investors may be watching for a fall into fear. This is natural because a rebound would become more probable the worse the sentiment gets now.

BTC Price
---------

During Bitcoin’s latest plunge, its price briefly slipped below $57,000 before surging back to $57,300.

![Image 7: Bitcoin Price Chart](https://www.tradingview.com/x/qM0dZAS0/)

Looks like the price of the asset has registered a sharp drop over the past two days | Source: [BTCUSD on TradingView](https://www.tradingview.com/chart/qFC1kfFd/)

Featured image from Kanchanara on Unsplash.com, Alternative.me, chart from TradingView.com

Disclaimer: The article is provided for educational purposes only. It does not represent the opinions of NewsBTC on whether to buy, sell or hold any investments and naturally investing carries risks. You are advised to conduct your own research before making any investment decisions. Use information provided on this website entirely at your own risk.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:41:57 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.newsbtc.com/bitcoin-news/bitcoin-greed-sentiment-neutral-57000-plunge/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Cardano Founder And Ripple CTO Go Head To Head Over XRP Regulations And ETHGate Allegations | Bitcoinist.com

URL Source: https://bitcoinist.com/cardano-founder-ripple-ethgate/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T11:00:39-05:00

Markdown Content:
[![Image 1: the bit starz logo on a black background](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=3854099)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2104699&amp;setID=579129&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=770131&amp;banID=521076925&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2029545&amp;adSize=150x45&amp;mt=1714581720644139&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fbitcoinist.com%2Fcardano-founder-ripple-ethgate%2F&amp;hc=cc540039cf5e9c6868b365234d31260209534ef3&amp;location=)

The crypto community is witnessing a virtual showdown between Cardano Founder, [Charles Hoskinson](https://bitcoinist.com/cardano-leadership-shakeup-charles-hoskinson/) and Ripple’s Chief Technology Officer (CTO), [David Schwartz](https://bitcoinist.com/one-project-man-ripple-cto-clarifies-where-his-loyalty-lays/). The two crypto giants are clashing over Ripple’s present regulatory challenges and the allegations surrounding the [ETH Gate](https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-watchdog-sues-sec-over-eth-gate/).  

Hoskinson And Schwartz Embark On Heated Debate
----------------------------------------------

Tensions have flared up within the crypto community as Hoskinson and Schwartz engaged in a [fiery debate](https://www.newsbtc.com/news/eth-gate-conversation-intensifies-after-ripple-cto-and-cardano-founder-debate/) over allegations of conspiracy within the Ethereum community and [Ripple’s ongoing legal battle](https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-lawsuit-sec-counters-ripple-motion-to-strike/) with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). 

[![Image 2: a banner with the words'bitstarz' and an image of a woman in a red dress](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=844202)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=1983102&amp;setID=367529&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=727083&amp;banID=520891527&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=1911064&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714581720646747&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fbitcoinist.com%2Fcardano-founder-ripple-ethgate%2F&amp;hc=c15aa05814ce05cc0cdbf456a4f5f56bbbd57739&amp;location=)

The controversy had begun when Hoskinson had publicly addressed rumors which claimed that the [Ethereum community had influenced the regulatory decisions](https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-insider-ripple-lawsuit-part-bigger-plan/) of the Ripple case by allegedly bribing the SEC to go after XRP. The Cardano founder had vehemently dismissed these allegations as unfounded conspiracy theories lacking credible evidence. 

In a swift rebuttal, Schwartz [raised questions](https://x.com/joelkatz/status/1784680727742963831?s=46) about a potential conflict of interest involving [William Hinman](https://bitcoinist.com/xrp-army-clues-hinman-ethereum-free-pass-ripple/), the former director of the US SEC. The Ripple CTO had implied that Hinman, having financial interests in Ethereum and recusing himself, may have swayed regulatory decisions in favor of Ethereum, potentially impacting the litigation against Ripple. 

“Aren’t the conventional ETH Gate arguments precisely about how it came to be that the SEC drew and interpreted the line in such a way that ETH was on the good side of it and XRP was on the bad side?” Schwartz inquired. 

[![Image 3: bbc iPlayer - screenshot](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4141110)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2392606&amp;setID=476001&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=878423&amp;banID=521869883&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2311166&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714581720647154&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fbitcoinist.com%2Fcardano-founder-ripple-ethgate%2F&amp;hc=cae214719c0e5ffc3a2ca61d23763fc4cccf240a&amp;location=)

Cardano Founder Faces Backlash From XRP Community
-------------------------------------------------

In a subsequent post, Hoskinson [criticized](https://x.com/iohk_charles/status/1784683970745213000?s=46) Schwartz for purportedly spreading false information regarding allegations about an Ethereum community’s influence on Ripple’s legal battle with the [US SEC](https://bitcoinist.com/ethereum-insider-sec-completely-rogue/). He clarified that he had never taken a stance on the rumors and arguments related to the ETH Gate, rather his statements have consistently revolved around the belief that someone within the [Ethereum community had bribed the SEC to target XRP.](https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/cardano-founder-ethgate-ethereum/) 

Responding to Hoskinson’s comment, an XRP supporter and crypto member [accused](https://x.com/quadjacksxrp/status/1784685849776468169?s=46) the Cardano founder of constantly using a preface in his posts to elicit sympathy rather than directly addressing the main problem. The member had also suggested that Hoskinson often portrays himself as a victim within the crypto community while refusing to change his opinions.

[![Image 4: a screen shot of a purple and blue background](https://servedbyadbutler.com/getad.img/;libID=4112488)](https://servedbyadbutler.com/redirect.spark?MID=172179&amp;plid=2368622&amp;setID=476002&amp;channelID=0&amp;CID=697928&amp;banID=521829420&amp;PID=0&amp;textadID=0&amp;tc=1&amp;scheduleID=2287404&amp;adSize=728x90&amp;mt=1714581720920808&amp;sw=800&amp;sh=600&amp;spr=1&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fbitcoinist.com%2Fcardano-founder-ripple-ethgate%2F&amp;hc=d7fff4a6ddbcea611679e42f7f571ea9b6cb9de6&amp;location=)

Related Reading: [Cardano Roars Back To Life As ADA Whales Move $13.84 Billion](https://bitcoinist.com/cardano-ada-whales-13-84-billion/)

Following this, Hoskinson challenged the XRP supporter, using explicit language to demand proof that supports the claims that a member of the [Ethereum community](https://www.newsbtc.com/news/ethereum/ethereum-whale-4-5-million-burn/) had directly influenced the legal proceedings of the Ripple and SEC case. 

Another community member also [accused](https://x.com/johnlen90858595/status/1784430057177432525?s=46) Hoskinson of misspeaking and misrepresenting the [allegations made by the XRP community](https://www.newsbtc.com/analysis/xrp/xrp-community-and-cardano-founder-engage-in-heated-clash/). The XRP supporter criticized the Cardano founder for aggravating the issues by insulting the XRP community and Schwartz, while simultaneously adopting a “narcissistic victim” stance. 

Hoskinson defended his position, [asserting](https://x.com/iohk_charles/status/1784433766615646407?s=46) that he did not misspeak, and solidified his belief that allegations involving the Ethereum community bribing the SEC were and “has always been a conspiracy theory.” 

![Image 5: ADA price chart from Tradingview.com (Ripple CTO Cardano founder)](https://www.tradingview.com/x/xkRycGK7/)

ADA price at $0.43 | Source: [ADAUSDT on Tradingview.com](http://tradingview.com/)

Featured image from Analytics Insight, chart from Tradingview.com

### Sign Up for Our Newsletter!

For updates and exclusive offers enter your email.

![Image 6: Scott Matherson](https://bitcoinist.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/Scott-Matherson.jpeg?resize=300%2C300)

Scott Matherson is a leading crypto writer at Bitcoinist, who possesses a sharp analytical mind and a deep understanding of the digital currency landscape. Scott has earned a reputation for delivering thought-provoking and well-researched articles that resonate with both newcomers and seasoned crypto enthusiasts. Outside of his writing, Scott is passionate about promoting crypto literacy and often works to educate the public on the potential of blockchain.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:42:22 GMT</pubDate><link>https://bitcoinist.com/cardano-founder-ripple-ethgate/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: DeFi lender Pike Finance loses $1.9M to two hacks in less than a week

URL Source: https://protos.com/defi-lender-pike-finance-loses-1-9m-to-two-hacks-in-less-than-a-week/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:47:57+00:00

Markdown Content:
Pike Finance has been hacked for the second time in four days, with losses across the two incidents totaling approximately $1.9 million.

In response to the first hack, on April 26, the team immediately paused the protocol. However, this opened up a new vulnerability that was exploited between 21:45 and 22:20 (UTC) on April 30.

Crypto security firm Ancilia quickly [identified](https://twitter.com/AnciliaInc/status/1785440926212751446) three malicious transactions on the [Optimism](https://optimistic.etherscan.io/tx/0x6baa6332f9a3ed75e727311d6317fb636844d61d9df5e199f9f68711eb632d6f), [Arbitrum](https://arbiscan.io/tx/0xdac6af5695ba00b3d229574dbf7fcc326d16b9f8a52ad2620637d3022956d157), and [Ethereum](https://etherscan.io/tx/0xe2912b8bf34d561983f2ae95f34e33ecc7792a2905a3e317fcc98052bce66431) networks. Ancilia [states](https://twitter.com/AnciliaInc/status/1785452418945429981) the attacker was able to ‘upgrade’ and take control of the Pike Finance contracts, which allowed them to withdraw the funds held within.

The stolen assets were **swapped to ETH** and [consolidated](https://etherscan.io/address/0x19066f7431df29a0910d287c8822936bb7d89e23#internaltx) in the attacker’s Ethereum [address](https://etherscan.io/address/0x19066f7431df29a0910d287c8822936bb7d89e23) before being [deposited](https://etherscan.io/tx/0xf8ce549fe83ecaf0d889ef5bda0b613081cefdad5bd82237e3a9014584a95d11) into privacy protocol Railgun.

Read more: [Hackers switching to centralized exchanges to fund crypto attacks](https://protos.com/hackers-switching-to-centralized-exchanges-to-fund-crypto-attacks/)

The hack was [acknowledged](https://twitter.com/PikeFinance/status/1785572875124330644) by the Pike team on X (formerly Twitter). The post put the losses at approximately **64k OP ($150,000), 100k ARB ($105,000), and 480 ETH ($1.4 million)** and admitted that the hack was related to the previous incident.

The last time Pike Finance was [hacked](https://twitter.com/PikeFinance/status/1783989069212799321) (three days ago), it suffered losses of around $300,000 worth of the USDC stablecoin. The resulting funds were swapped for ETH and transferred to the crypto-mixing service Tornado Cash.

According to the earlier incident’s [post-mortem report](https://mirror.xyz/pikefinance.eth/M1ToE42vwEHuE6xlz0dVRQwPT0xpaRtpIIw2arOdBAM), the protocol was paused to prevent any further losses while the incident was investigated. The report also admits that the vulnerability had been reported by auditors OtterSec, but that the Pike team “was unable to address the identified vulnerability in a timely manner.”

However, as described in today’s [response](https://twitter.com/PikeFinance/status/1785572875124330644) to the second hack, pausing the contracts inadvertently introduced “an additional dependency within the smart contract code.” This led to a “misalignment in storage mapping” which the attacker could take advantage of, reinitializing the contract and assuming full control.

Pike Finance has offered a **20% bounty for the return of the funds** and has promised to provide a “plan to make users whole.”

The community’s opinions on this response can be seen in the Pike Finance Discord.

![Image 1: a black screen with emojis on it](https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdAnEfzBJwt7tS3R1W1vRjp3k9dv9Kbktlxwb1Jy8bTroqsiLcyW0kC7NTUKb9TLeFvQS3fjxTP7VL0zEGLhrsacFQLUCkM-_OhOoZgrL4iER7Z8QCoQ_5jEkdgCchxL2ckDYNK5nCjhUbV_dNGVDHjT2dB?key=UdeyZSePlEFr4v8PVZRAoQ)

_Read more: [Tornado Cash funds ‘at risk’ after hacker injects malicious code](https://protos.com/tornado-cash-funds-at-risk-after-hacker-injects-malicious-code/)_

After being hit twice in a row, users are understandably upset, and [some](https://twitter.com/deucesofweb3/status/1785576987550957856) have [suggested](https://twitter.com/Picolas_Caged/status/1785581065693778260) that Pike Finance refund pre-sale investments.

This in itself has, [predictably](https://twitter.com/PikeFinance/status/1785607580146163876), opened up another potential attack vector as scam replies (impersonating the Pike Finance account) promise a refund to victims as part of a common phishing technique.

_Got a tip? Send us an email or ProtonMail. For more informed news, follow us on [X](https://twitter.com/protos), [Instagram](https://www.instagram.com/protosmedia/), [Bluesky](https://bsky.app/profile/protos.bsky.social), and [_Google News_](https://news.google.com/publications/CAAqBwgKMLmroQsw0bW5Aw), or subscribe to our [YouTube](https://youtube.com/protosmedia) channel._
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:44:04 GMT</pubDate><link>https://protos.com/defi-lender-pike-finance-loses-1-9m-to-two-hacks-in-less-than-a-week/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: 'Dogecoin Millionaire' Says 'Fair Launches' For Meme Coins Don't Exist: 'Stop Being Delusional'

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38556972/dogecoin-millionaire-says-fair-launches-for-meme-coins-dont-exist-stop-being-delusional

Published Time: 2024-05-01T11:43:05.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
Las Vegas resident **Glauber Contessoto**, famously known as the "[Dogecoin Millionaire](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/23/08/34016792/dogecoin-millionaires-holdings-drop-from-3m-to-50k-but-remains-optimistic-says-doge-will-r),” took to his social media account to throw light on the concept of fair launches in the crypto markets.

**What Happened:** The heavily followed trader argues that the presence of snipers and bots has created an uneven playing field, making it nearly impossible for average investors to compete.

"These days, there is no such thing as a fair launch," Contessoto asserts. "Snipers, people who use bots and are fucking professional at it, are who you’re going against when a coin launches." He emphasizes that, this cannot be considered a fair launch, as these players are not adhering to the same rules as regular investors.

He further warns that attempting to participate in these launches is a surefire way to lose money, stating, "They’re not playing by the same rules as you, and you will lose money 100% of the time. Stop being completely delusional." He paints a picture of snipers waiting on the sidelines, ready to "crush and destroy a project the second it goes live."

[![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)](https://www.benzinga.com/events/digital-assets/)

_Also Read: [Meme Coins Are ‘A Pure Ponzi’ And ‘Destroying Crypto,’ Says Trader Who Thinks Dogecoin Was Different](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/04/38469336/meme-coins-are-a-pure-ponzi-and-destroying-crypto-says-trader-who-thinks-dogecoin-was-diff)_

**Why It Matters:** For the betterment of the situation, Contessoto suggests that the best outcome investors can hope for is to support projects with solid teams that understand the challenges posed by snipers and bots.

He advises teams to take proactive measures to protect their projects and communities. They could buy up most of the supply and distribute it over time, allowing the project to grow naturally with a thriving community as the market cap rises.

His suggestion to investors is to focus on these types of projects rather than chasing the so-called "fair launches" that are vulnerable to snipers and bots. He also warns that as soon as the snipers dump their bags within hours of launch, they move on to the next coin that they can demolish and make endless money.

Contessoto famously watched his fortune take a drastic plunge from $3 million to as low as $50,000 when he did not sell his **Dogecoin** DOGE/USD holdings after a massive run-up.

**What’s Next**: The influence of meme coins and [Bitcoin as an institutional asset class](https://www.benzinga.com/money/is-bitcoin-a-good-investment) is expected to be thoroughly explored at Benzinga’s upcoming [Future of Digital Assets](https://www.benzinga.com/events/digital-assets/agenda/) event on Nov. 19.

_Read Next: [Crypto Trader Michael Van De Poppe Highlights Runs In Solana, Meme Coins, Predicts ‘There Is Always An Altcoin Season’](https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/04/38523300/crypto-trader-michael-van-de-poppe-highlights-runs-in-solana-meme-coins-predicts-there-is-)_

_This content was partially produced with the help of AI tools and was reviewed and published by Benzinga editors._

_Image: Shutterstock_

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:44:29 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/markets/cryptocurrency/24/05/38556972/dogecoin-millionaire-says-fair-launches-for-meme-coins-dont-exist-stop-being-delusional?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Solana (SOL) Price Prediction for May 1

URL Source: https://u.today/solana-sol-price-prediction-for-may-1

Published Time: 2024-05-01T15:38:00+0000

Markdown Content:
Original U.Today article

![Image 1: Solana (SOL) Price Prediction for May 1](https://u.today/sites/default/files/styles/736x/public/2024-05/s2193.jpg)

Cover image via [www.tradingview.com](https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/SOLUSD/)

Disclaimer: The opinions expressed by our writers are their own and do not represent the views of U.Today. The financial and market information provided on U.Today is intended for informational purposes only. U.Today is not liable for any financial losses incurred while trading cryptocurrencies. Conduct your own research by contacting financial experts before making any investment decisions. We believe that all content is accurate as of the date of publication, but certain offers mentioned may no longer be available.

The prices of most of the coins keep falling, according to [CoinStats](https://u.today/shib-price-prediction-for-april-30).

![Image 2: a screen showing the solar price chart](https://u.today/sites/default/files/inline-images/top10_1089.png)

SOL chart by [CoinStats](https://coinstats.app/coins/)

SOL/USD
-------

The price of Solana (SOL) has declined by 4% over the last day.

![Image 3: btc - btc - btc - btc - btc -](https://u.today/sites/default/files/inline-images/sol1_32.png)

Image by [TradingView](https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/SOLUSDT)

On the hourly chart, the rate of SOL is in the middle of the local channel, between the support of $118.47 and the resistance of $127.33. 

As most of the daily ATR has been passed, there are low chances to expect any sharp ups or downs by the end of the day.

![Image 4: btc/usd - btc/usd - btc/usd - bt](https://u.today/sites/default/files/inline-images/sol2_28.png)

Image by [TradingView](https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/SOLUSDT)

On the bigger time frame, traders should focus on the bar's closure in terms of yesterday's low at $121.21. If a false breakout happens, one can expect a bounce back to the $130 zone within the next few days.

![Image 5: btc btc btc btc btc btc btc b](https://u.today/sites/default/files/inline-images/sol3_28.png)

Image by [TradingView](https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/SOLUSDT)

On the weekly chart, there are no reversal signals yet. The price of SOL is approaching the recently formed level of $116. If buyers cannot seize the initiative by the end of the week, the accumulated energy might be enough for a move to the crucial zone of $100.

SOL is trading at $122.43 at press time.

[![Image 6: article image](https://u.today/sites/default/files/2021-08/8942.jpg)

Denys Serhiichuk

](https://u.today/denys-serhiichuk)

With more than 5 years of trading, Denys has a deep knowledge of both technical and fundamental market analysis. Mainly, he has started his blog on TradingView where publishes all relevant information and makes predictions about top coins.  
Thus, his experience is backed up by working in top blockchain related companies such as W12, Platinum Listing, ATB Coin, and others, can be contacted at denys.serhiichuk@u.today.

Advertisement

TopCryptoNewsinYourMailbox

TopCryptoNewsinYourMailbox
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:45:31 GMT</pubDate><link>https://u.today/solana-sol-price-prediction-for-may-1</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: CBN's KYC audit sends shockwaves through Nigerian Fintech

URL Source: https://www.cryptopolitan.com/kyc-sends-shockwave-through-nigerian-fintech/

Markdown Content:
Four well-known fintech companies have received orders from the Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN) to stop onboarding new clients. This mandate is part of a larger audit of OPay, Kuda Bank, Moniepoint, and PalmPay’s KYC procedures.

KYC concerns prompt temporary onboarding pause
----------------------------------------------

The CBN directive [influenced](https://techcabal.com/2024/04/29/exclusive-cbn-directs-four-fintechs-to-stop-onboarding/) the operation of these fintech platforms, “they have been put on hold for the time being, meaning those who would have had new accounts cannot continue. 

Each website features a notice of apology, indicating no disgrace on their account for the momentary interruption that affected them. Because no new customers are to be acquired, the continuing operation and the existing customers’ deposits remain safe and sound.”

The move entails the Central Bank devising measures reflecting a series of events in which the legitimacy of the fintech platform was called into question due to loose KYC regulations. 

The story goes back to Fidelity Bank in October 2023, which had similar concerns about fraudulent activities restricting OPay, PalmPay, Kuda, and MonieP transactions. In turn, the banking authority implemented new KYC rules for any related financial institutions, and they focused on fintech startups as the most prominent threat.

Government crackdown on Fintech
-------------------------------

Government involvement in the fintech industry is practically the CBN directive. The alignment of the National Security Agency (NSA) and economic-related fraud agencies like the Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC) in the battle against financial misdoings exposes their undeniable effort to eradicate such acts. 

The EFCC’s recent blocking of over a thousand accounts involved in unauthorized foreign exchange market transactions clearly shows the extra regulatory attention the financial sector is now subject to. The industry has mixed reactions, from cautious optimism to concerns about intensifying trade tensions. 

While some industries welcome the assistance afforded by higher domestic production requirements to strengthen their competitive edge, others fear that worldwide trade relations may become increasingly complicated.

Although stopping the enrollment of a new customer base may disrupt business operations, the independent decision by the regulators is the right move in that it guards against regulatory infringements as it safeguards the financial risks. 

The recently conducted audit of KYC procedures is undoubtedly evidence of the industry’s determination and commitment to ensuring regulatory oversight.

Regulatory evolution
--------------------

However, amid these interventions, several positive policies and programs are currently being implemented within Nigeria’s financial regulatory structure.

The appointment of Emomotimi Agama as the new Director General of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) by the crypto community and investors not only for the recent economy but also for the future’s crypto economy is considered by cryptocurrency enthusiasts as an optimistic move. 

The appointment fosters devotion among investors, controls the capital market, and accelerates economic growth. The regulatory authority and fintech start-ups are expected to collaborate to expedite the process of acquiring licenses to operate crypto exchanges in Nigeria. 

Some stakeholders view the selection of Emomotimi Agama as a positive outcome that vows to open a new chapter of consensus between regulators and the crypto industry, which should result in an appropriate framework for innovation and growth.

The CBN’s resoluteness against the currently ongoing activities of e-currency firms, which has led to the central bank’s ban on their customer onboarding operations, further explains the necessity of the KYC process for the financial system. Although they might be less desirable in the short run, such regulatory measures were intended to control standards of compliance and financial risks.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:46:20 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.cryptopolitan.com/kyc-sends-shockwave-through-nigerian-fintech/</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Disqus Realtime Notification

URL Source: https://tokenist.com/chip-stocks-plunge-after-amds-2024-guidance-falls-short-of-expectations/

Markdown Content:
\-
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:46:45 GMT</pubDate><link>https://tokenist.com/chip-stocks-plunge-after-amds-2024-guidance-falls-short-of-expectations/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=chip-stocks-plunge-after-amds-2024-guidance-falls-short-of-expectations</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: An ETH ETF Wouldn’t Deliver Full-Returns to Investors

URL Source: https://www.coindesk.com/business/2024/05/01/an-eth-etf-wouldnt-deliver-full-returns-to-investors/

Published Time: 2024-05-01T16:00:00Z

Markdown Content:
_ETFs bring awareness but are less effective than private funds as an ETH investment vehicle._

With the recent approval, launch and success of [spot bitcoin ETFs](https://www.coindesk.com/markets/2024/04/19/bitcoin-spot-etfs-register-five-day-withdrawals-streak-ahead-of-halving/), all eyes have turned to the possibility of spot ETH ETF regulatory approval, an outcome we believe to be unlikely under the current administration. Additionally, an ETH ETF will, at least initially, lack a staking reward component, a key aspect of ETH total return.

We see the primary value of crypto-ETFs being the _normalization_ of crypto investing for traditional finance allocators. Large ETF providers entering the space license their legitimacy, allowing allocators to invest in crypto without taking career-risk. However, for all the industry benefits of a spot ETH ETF, the return characteristics are not as attractive as total return options.

At the time of writing, rewards from staking eth are over 3% per annum, according to [CESR, the benchmark composite ether staking rate](https://www.coindesk.com/indices/ether/cesr/). In other words, if an investor invests into an ETH ETF, they may be at a disadvantage compared to someone investing in a staked investment. CESR has been as high as 8% in the trailing twelve months.

**You're reading** [**Crypto Long &amp; Short**](https://www.coindesk.com/newsletters/crypto-long-short/)**, our weekly newsletter featuring insights, news and analysis for the professional investor.** [**Sign up here**](https://www.coindesk.com/newsletters/crypto-long-short/) **to get it in your inbox every Wednesday.**

**ETH ETFs — A liquidity mismatch due to staking**

Mechanically, staking reduces liquidity due to the validator entry and exit queues. In the summer of 2023 the entry queue rose to 45 days due to a surge in activity. As a network security activity, staking is not designed with the liquidity needed for securitization in mind. Due to the immense liquidity demands of an ETF, issuers will struggle to deliver liquidity and ETH total return, including staking rewards.

**Structural Underperformance**

Passively holding unstaked ETH is akin to holding unneeded fiat currency for long periods in a demand deposit account with zero interest. Said another way, passively holding unstaked ETH will create structural underperformance and, if compared to a total return benchmark, persistent negative tracking error. From any angle, that is an untenable position for an investor.

For accredited investors, private funds offer an effective solution to achieve total return ETH exposure. Buying and staking ETH through a private fund structure does not face regulatory challenges. Managers can also match the liquidity of the fund to stake and unstake ETH on behalf of investors. With a thoughtful operational setup, there are limited tradeoffs; a private fund can be audited, benchmarked, and keep assets in qualified custody.

Disclosure: Methodic [partnered](https://www.coindesk.com/business/2023/10/18/investment-manager-methodic-unveils-ether-staking-fund-offering-exposure-to-eth-price-and-yield/) with CoinDesk's index affiliate, CoinDesk Indices, on a private fund that uses the CoinDesk Ether Total Return Index, a combination of the [CoinDesk Ether Price Index (ETX)](https://www.coindesk.com/indices/etx?_gl=1*5n27e0*_up*MQ..*_ga*MTM0MTI3Njc3LjE2OTc1NjUyMzQ.*_ga_VM3STRYVN8*MTY5NzU2NTIzNC4xLjAuMTY5NzU2NTIzNC4wLjAuMA..) and the [Composite Ether Staking Rate (CESR)](https://www.coindesk.com/indices/ether/cesr/), calculated by CoinDesk Indices and administered by digital asset manager CoinFund.

Edited by Benjamin Schiller.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:47:37 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.coindesk.com/business/2024/05/01/an-eth-etf-wouldnt-deliver-full-returns-to-investors/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Coinbase Up 300% In A Year, But Faces Bearish Technicals Ahead Of Q1 Earnings - Coinbase Glb (NASDAQ:COIN

URL Source: https://www.benzinga.com/analyst-ratings/analyst-color/24/05/38557434/coinbase-up-300-in-a-year-but-faces-bearish-technicals-ahead-of-q1-earnings

Published Time: 2024-05-01T11:59:23.000-04:00

Markdown Content:
**Coinbase Global Inc** COIN, will be reporting its first-quarter earnings on Thursday. Wall Street expects $1.00 in EPS and $1.34 billion in revenues as the company reports [after market hours](https://www.benzinga.com/calendars/earnings?tickers=COIN).

The stock has gained over 300% in the past year, riding with the crypto boom. The stock’s surge compares favorably to Bitcoin’s price, which rose by 103.13% over the past year. YTD, shares have returned 17.13%, lagging behind Bitcoin’s 30% stride.

Let’s look at what the charts indicate for Coinbase stock, and how the stock currently maps against Wall Street estimates.

**Coinbase Stock’s Bearish Signals Ahead Of Q1 Earnings** 
----------------------------------------------------------

Charts indicate that the current trend for Coinbase stock is relatively bearish.

![Image 1: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

_[Chart: Benzinga Pro](https://pro.benzinga.com/dashboard)_

Its share price at $203.40, is trading below key moving averages. The 5-day exponential moving average (EMA) at $213.25, the 20-day EMA at $226.46, and 50-day EMA at $219.61, indicate selling pressure and a risk of future bearish movement.

Coinbase stock is also trading below the 8-day and 50-day simple moving averages (SMA), all of which suggest a bearish momentum. However, the stock is above the 200-day SMA of $137.69, indicating a bullish signal.

![Image 2: a black background with a plane flying in the sky](data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAIAAAAAAAP///yH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAABAAEAAAIBRAA7)

_[Chart: Benzinga Pro](https://pro.benzinga.com/dashboard)_

The Moving Average Convergence Divergence (MACD) indicator is -6.11, suggesting a strongly bearish sentiment. The Relative Strength Index (RSI) of 40.64 is in the Neutral zone. However, since March, the RSI has been heading lower, so it could enter the oversold (&lt;30) zone in the near-term. That could potentially be bullish for the stock, if supported by other indicators.

The Bollinger Bands have Coinbase stock trading in their lower band – indicating trader bearishness dominating the stock.

Overall, the technical indicators suggest a bearish trend for Coinbase stock, but with potential trend reversal opportunities once the RSI enters the oversold zone.

_Also Read: [What the Options Market Tells Us About Coinbase Glb](https://www.benzinga.com/insights/options/24/04/38384275/what-the-options-market-tells-us-about-coinbase-glb)_

**Coinbase Stock Analysts See 34% Upside**
------------------------------------------

**Ratings &amp; Consensus Estimates:** [The consensus analyst rating](https://www.benzinga.com/quote/COIN/analyst-ratings) on Coinbase stock stands at a Buy with a price target of $169.08. However, the latest analyst ratings for Coinbase stock from HC Wainwright &amp; Co., Bernstein, and Compass Point, received in April, point toward a greener picture. These analysts have an average price target of $275, suggesting a potential upside of 34.02% for Coinbase stock.

**COIN Price Action:** Shares of Coinbase are down 1.34% to $201.20 at the time of publication Wednesday.

_Read Next: [Coinbase Global To Rally Around 27%? Here Are 10 Top Analyst Forecasts For Monday](https://www.benzinga.com/news/24/04/38489083/coinbase-global-to-rally-around-27-here-are-10-top-analyst-forecasts-for-monday)_

_Photo: Shutterstock_

[Market News and Data brought to you by Benzinga APIs](https://benzinga.com/apis)

© 2024 Benzinga.com. Benzinga does not provide investment advice. All rights reserved.
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:48:41 GMT</pubDate><link>https://www.benzinga.com/analyst-ratings/analyst-color/24/05/38557434/coinbase-up-300-in-a-year-but-faces-bearish-technicals-ahead-of-q1-earnings?utm_source=cryptopanic.com&amp;utm_campaign=partner_feed&amp;utm_medium=partner_feed&amp;utm_content=site</link></item><item><title>News Article 52</title><description>Title: Eminem's new crypto ad fails to capture the moment, lets it slip

URL Source: https://blockworks.co/news/eminem-cryptocom-advertisement-silly

Markdown Content:
![Image 1: off topic with molly jane](https://blockworks-co.imgix.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Off-Topic-with-Molly-Jane_20230616a-1.png?w=1024&amp;h=1024)

This isn’t going to be another op-ed about how silly it is for celebrities to do cryptocurrency ads. We all know that they don’t age well.

Instead, what I’d like to opine on is why a cryptocurrency ad with Marshall Mathers, aka Eminem, falls flat in particular. If you’re going to put a celebrity in your crypto ad, you need to go all out with creativity, humor or just overall entertainment value. Eminem’s new crypto ad does none of that — it has almost nothing to do with the rapper, or crypto at all.

The rapper’s voiceover on an [advertisement for Crypto.com](http://crypto.com/) aired during the Lakers NBA play-off game last week. The ad itself, just a minute long, shows a nameless, faceless boxer getting ready to face-off in a match at the Crypto.com Arena. You can hear Eminem’s voice saying empty platitudes of encouragement in the background, telling the audience to enjoy the moment, before the screen shows the somewhat infamous slogan, “Fortune favors the brave.”

I say infamous, because Matt Damon’s 2022 Crypto.com SuperBowl commercial — where the Oscar-nominated actor was actually pictured on screen saying that catchphrase out loud — just looked so silly in the wake of the FTX crash. Damon later gave an [awkward, pause-filled red carpet interview](https://gizmodo.com/matt-damon-crypto-com-crypto-bitcoin-1850282413), noting that he only did the commercial to support his water non-profit in a down year.

Some are [already speculating](https://www.stereogum.com/2261473/eminem-is-crypto-coms-new-spokesman-teases-new-album-the-death-of-slim-shady/news/) that Eminem’s main motivation to lend his voice to Crypto.com’s latest ad is part of a marketing push for his upcoming album. But his motivations for being crypto’s latest celebrity spokesperson aren’t important. What’s important is how soulless that advertisement is. Watching the commercial for the first time as a longtime Eminem stan, I lamented all of the missed opportunities staring me in the face.

**Read more from our opinion section:** [Crypto’s best use case? Buying goats on Twitter](https://blockworks.co/news/cryptos-best-use-case-buying-goats-twitter)

For one, this is far from Eminem’s first foray into crypto — he had his own, pretty cringey Bored Ape phase at the peak of the NFT boom, culminating in a [half-animated BAYT music video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RjrA-slMoZ4) with none other than Snoop Dogg. That was terrible, and also funny: and Crypto.com’s pretty basic ad could have benefitted from any sort of creative reference to Eminem’s actual crypto interests. 

Granted, Crypto.com is not an NFT platform. That doesn’t mean that you aren’t allowed to have a sense of humor — especially when creating a likely very expensive advertisement with a very famous, previously NFT-obsessed rapper.

Which brings me to my second point — there’s no rap. Paying Eminem to remain faceless and read a short, only slightly rhyming text over a black-and-white boxing video feels like paying [Bob Dylan to promote Victoria’s Secret](https://www.thecut.com/2019/07/i-think-about-bob-dylans-victorias-secret-ad-a-lot.html).

Eminem’s crypto ad isn’t the first since the unfortunate crypto Super Bowl. Both Coinbase and Greyscale also [put out slightly more entertaining ads](https://blockworks.co/news/nba-nhl-bitcoin-halving-ads) in the lead up to the Bitcoin halving, albeit celebrity-less ones. 

As I said at the top, my point here isn’t to convince the world that celebrities in crypto ads are setting themselves up for [future embarrassment](https://blockworks.co/news/celebrities-erase-ftx-ties), [loss of money](https://blockworks.co/news/what-do-tom-brady-steph-curry-and-naomi-osaka-have-in-common-an-ftx-lawsuit) and even potentially [SEC fines](https://www.sec.gov/news/press-release/2022-183). We already know that. And I also know that no one will stop crypto companies, especially during a bull market, from paying celebrities tons of money to promote their brands anyway. Sam Bankman-Fried set that precedent, and even with him in jail, it really shows no signs of abating.

Instead, I’d like to propose that if we are going to keep having celeb-studded crypto ads — make them really sparkle. Pay Eminem to write an entire song about trading on Crypto.com and release it alongside his new album, with a specially crypto-themed music video (he already has the experience). Get JoJo Siwa to [wrap another car](https://www.tiktok.com/@itsjojosiwa/video/7352686405887331630) with whatever memecoin logo, or Brooklyn Beckham to tattoo Dogecoin eyes next to his [tattoo of his wife’s eyes](https://pagesix.com/article/brooklyn-beckham-tattoos-for-nicola-peltz/).

Celebrity crypto ads, in my opinion, should only exist if they do something really creative or really silly: In other words, make them match the whimsy and creativity of this burgeoning financial tech industry. I’m not sure that any SEC lawyers would agree with me. Good thing I don’t work for the SEC.

Otherwise, make celebrity crypto endorsements illegal for all of the obvious reasons (high potential for securities fraud and misleading investors to start). In a nutshell — go silly or go home.

* * *

_I don’t care much about tech, I don’t care a whole lot about finance, either. I care about writing stories and watching weird things unfold. And that’s why I’ve ended up in crypto._

_But because I’m missing that passion for what crypto and blockchain are all about — finance, tech, privacy, yadda yadda — I’m going to write instead about what I am actually interested in. Everything about crypto that has very little to do with crypto._

_That’s what this column will be about. All the tangential stories that come out of the blockchain and crypto space, what I think about them, and how I navigate it all as a skeptical former Russian literature major._

_It’s precisely my perch as an outsider that lets me do what I do: Opine on all sides of any crypto issue, no strings attached, no skin in the game._

_If you want to talk crypto with me, let’s go off topic._

* * *

**Start your day with top crypto insights from David Canellis and Katherine Ross. [Subscribe to the Empire newsletter](https://blockworks.co/newsletter/empire).**

Tags

*   [celebrity](https://blockworks.co/tag/celebrity)
*   [Crypto.com](https://blockworks.co/tag/cryptocom)
*   [cryptocurrency](https://blockworks.co/tag/cryptocurrency)
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 16:49:08 GMT</pubDate><link>https://blockworks.co/news/eminem-cryptocom-advertisement-silly</link></item></channel>
</rss>